<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="110" type="h" number="1078" abbrev="H.R. 1078"><status date="2007-02-15">introduced</status><introduced date="2007-02-15"/><title>Comprehensive Cancer Care Improvement Act of 2007</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="110" type="s" number="2790"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>Health policy</subject><subject>Administrative procedure</subject><subject>Aged</subject><subject>Budgets</subject><subject>Cancer</subject><subject>Case management</subject><subject>Communication in medicine</subject><subject>Communications</subject><subject>Comprehensive health care</subject><subject>Congressional reporting requirements</subject><subject>Continuing education</subject><subject>Department of Health and Human Services</subject><subject>Education</subject><subject>Educational accountability</subject><subject>Executive departments</subject><subject>Federal aid to education</subject><subject>Federal aid to health facilities</subject><subject>Federal aid to research</subject><subject>Graduate education</subject><subject>Health planning</subject><subject>Higher education</subject><subject>Home care services</subject><subject>Law</subject><subject>Medical care</subject><subject>Medical education</subject><subject>Medical fees</subject><subject>Medical research</subject><subject>Medicare</subject><subject>Medicine</subject><subject>Nurses</subject><subject>Nursing education</subject><subject>Physicians</subject><subject>Psychologists</subject><subject>Research grants</subject><subject>Science policy</subject><subject>Standards</subject><subject>Terminal care</subject></subjects><summary>2/15/2007--Introduced.
Comprehensive Cancer Care Improvement Act of 2007 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to provide for coverage of comprehensive cancer care planning services to provide individuals diagnosed with cancer a plan that details all aspects of the care to be provided. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish standards for such services.
Directs the Secretary to conduct a two-year demonstration project under which Medicare payments will be made for comprehensive cancer care symptom management services furnished by an eligible entity in accordance with a described plan.
Directs the Secretary to make grants to eligible entities to: (1) establish new, or expand existing, palliative care and symptom management programs for cancer patients; (2) improve the quality of graduate and postgraduate training of physicians, nurses, and other health care providers in palliative care and symptom management for such patients; and (3) improve the quality of continuing professional education provided to qualified individuals regarding palliative care and symptom management for cancer patients.
Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to establish a program of grants for research on palliative care, symptom management, communication skills, and other end-of-life topics for such patients.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c110:H.R.1078:"/></bill>
