<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="110" type="h" number="1193" abbrev="H.R. 1193"><status date="2007-02-27">introduced</status><introduced date="2007-02-27"/><title>Kidney Care Quality and Education Act of 2007</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="110" type="s" number="691"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>Medicine</subject><subject>Access to health care</subject><subject>Aged</subject><subject>Budgets</subject><subject>Child health</subject><subject>Children</subject><subject>Chronically ill</subject><subject>Congressional reporting requirements</subject><subject>Executive departments</subject><subject>Federal advisory bodies</subject><subject>Federal aid to research</subject><subject>Government information</subject><subject>Government paperwork</subject><subject>Government publicity</subject><subject>Governmental investigations</subject><subject>Health education</subject><subject>Health facilities</subject><subject>Health information systems</subject><subject>Health policy</subject><subject>Health surveys</subject><subject>Home care services</subject><subject>Hospital rates</subject><subject>Inspectors general</subject><subject>Job training</subject><subject>Kidney diseases</subject><subject>Law</subject><subject>Licenses</subject><subject>Medical care</subject><subject>Medical economics</subject><subject>Medical fees</subject><subject>Medical personnel</subject><subject>Medical research</subject><subject>Medical supplies</subject><subject>Medicare</subject><subject>Physicians</subject><subject>Politics and government</subject><subject>Preventive medicine</subject><subject>Quality of care</subject><subject>Quality of life</subject><subject>Science policy</subject><subject>Self-care</subject><subject>Technical education</subject><subject>Transplantation of organs, tissues, etc.</subject></subjects><summary>2/27/2007--Introduced.
Kidney Care Quality and Education Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish demonstration projects to: (1) increase public awareness about the factors that lead to chronic kidney disease, how to prevent it, how to treat it, and how to avoid kidney failure, as well as enhance surveillance systems and expand research to better assess the prevalence and incidence of kidney disease; and (2) enable individuals with end-stage renal disease (ESRD) to develop self-management skills. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to provide for Medicare coverage of kidney disease patient education services.
Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish blood flow monitoring demonstration projects; and (2) arrange with the Institute of Medicine of the National Academy of Sciences to evaluate the barriers to increasing the number of individuals with ESRD who elect to receive home dialysis services or other treatment modalities under Medicare. Sets forth required training for patient care dialysis technicians.
Directs the Secretary to establish an independent, multidisciplinary, nonpartisan End-Stage Renal Disease Advisory Committee. Establishes the annual update framework for the Medicare ESRD composite rate. Directs the Secretary to establish a three-year continuous quality improvement initiative under which quality payments are provided to renal dialysis facilities, providers of services, and physicians that: (1) provide items and services to individuals with ESRD enrolled under Medicare part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance); and (2) meet quality benchmarks and demonstrate quality improvements. Requires the Secretary to make quality incentive payments to facilities and providers whose services to individuals with ESRD have substantially improved or exceeded a certain threshold. Extends Medicare as secondary payer with respect to individuals with ESRD.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c110:H.R.1193:"/></bill>
