<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="111" type="h" number="1032" abbrev="H.R. 1032"><status date="2010-09-30T00:43:00-04:00">vote</status><introduced date="2009-02-12"/><title>Heart Disease Education, Analysis Research, and Treatment for Women Act</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="111" type="s" number="422"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>Health</subject><subject>Cardiovascular and respiratory health</subject><subject>Congressional oversight</subject><subject>Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation</subject><subject>Government information and archives</subject><subject>Health care quality</subject><subject>Health information and medical records</subject><subject>Health programs administration and funding</subject><subject>Health promotion and preventive care</subject><subject>Licensing and registrations</subject><subject>Medical education</subject><subject>Medical research</subject><subject>Prescription drugs</subject><subject>Women's health</subject></subjects><summary>9/30/2010--Passed House amended. Heart Disease Education, Analysis Research, and Treatment for Women Act or the HEART for Women Act - (Sec. 2) Directs to the Comptroller General to study and report to specified congressional committees on the extent to which sponsors of clinical studies of investigational drugs, biologics, and devices and sponsors of applications for approval or licensure of new drugs, biologics, and devices comply with Food and Drug Administration (FDA) requirements and follow guidance for presentation of clinical study safety and effectiveness data by sex, age, and racial subgroups. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to submit to such committees a response to the the Comptroller General's report, including a corrective action plan as needed to respond to the recommendations in such report. (Sec. 3) Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary to report to Congress on the quality of, and access to, care for women with heart disease, stroke, and other cardiovascular diseases, including recommendations for eliminating disparities in, and improving the treatment of, heart disease, stroke, and other cardiovascular diseases in women. (Sec. 4) Expands and reauthorizes appropriations for FY2012-FY2016 for a program to award grants for preventive heath services and referrals for medical treatment for women through entities that are screening women for breast or cervical cancer.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c111:H.R.1032:"/></bill>
