<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="112" type="h" number="1090" abbrev="H.R. 1090"><status date="2011-03-15">introduced</status><introduced date="2011-03-15"/><title>Full-Service Community Schools Act of 2011</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="112" type="s" number="585"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>Education</subject><subject>Academic performance and assessments</subject><subject>Adult education and literacy</subject><subject>Advisory bodies</subject><subject>Child care and development</subject><subject>Child health</subject><subject>Community life and organization</subject><subject>Crime prevention</subject><subject>Education of the disadvantaged</subject><subject>Education programs funding</subject><subject>Elementary and secondary education</subject><subject>Employment and training programs</subject><subject>Family relationships</subject><subject>Health care coverage and access</subject><subject>Homelessness and emergency shelter</subject><subject>Juvenile crime and gang violence</subject><subject>Mental health</subject><subject>Nutrition and diet</subject><subject>Performance measurement</subject><subject>Physical fitness and lifestyle</subject><subject>Preschool education</subject><subject>Public-private cooperation</subject><subject>School administration</subject></subjects><summary>3/15/2011--Introduced.
Full-Service Community Schools Act of 2011 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary of Education to award grants to: (1) consortia composed of one or more local educational agencies (LEAs) and one or more community-based, nonprofit, or other public or private entities to assist public elementary or secondary schools to function as full-service community schools; and (2) state collaboratives to support the development of full-service community school programs. Requires such schools to: (1) participate in community-based efforts to coordinate and integrate educational, developmental, family, health, and other comprehensive services through community-based organizations and public and private partnerships; and (2) provide access to such services to students, families, and the community. Gives local grant priority to consortia that: (1) will serve at least one full-service community school eligible for a schoolwide program under the Act, or include an LEA serving only small or rural schools; and (2) will be connected to a consortium comprising a broad representation of stakeholders or one that has a history of effectiveness. Establishes a Full-Service Community Schools Advisory Committee.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c112:H.R.1090:"/></bill>
