<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="112" type="h" number="1" abbrev="H.R. 1"><status date="2011-02-19T04:40:00-05:00">vote</status><introduced date="2011-02-11"/><title>Full-Year Continuing Appropriations Act, 2011</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="112" type="hr" number="92"/><relatedbill session="112" type="hr" number="92"/><relatedbill session="112" type="h" number="1473"/><relatedbill session="112" type="h" number="5856"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>Economics and public finance</subject><subject>Abortion</subject><subject>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</subject><subject>Advanced technology and technological innovations</subject><subject>Afghanistan</subject><subject>Agricultural conservation and pollution</subject><subject>Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit</subject><subject>Alaska</subject><subject>Alternative and renewable resources</subject><subject>Appalachian Regional Commission</subject><subject>Appropriations</subject><subject>Architect of the Capitol</subject><subject>Arms control and nonproliferation</subject><subject>Asia</subject><subject>Caribbean area</subject><subject>Central Intelligence Agency (CIA)</subject><subject>Climate change and greenhouse gases</subject><subject>Coal</subject><subject>Congressional Budget Office (CBO)</subject><subject>Congressional Research Service (CRS)</subject><subject>Congressional agencies</subject><subject>Congressional operations and organization</subject><subject>Consumer Financial Protection Bureau</subject><subject>Cuba</subject><subject>Defense spending</subject><subject>Delta Regional Authority</subject><subject>Denali Commission</subject><subject>Department of Agriculture</subject><subject>Department of Commerce</subject><subject>Department of Defense</subject><subject>Department of Education</subject><subject>Department of Energy</subject><subject>Department of Health and Human Services</subject><subject>Department of Homeland Security</subject><subject>Department of Housing and Urban Development</subject><subject>Department of Justice</subject><subject>Department of Labor</subject><subject>Department of State</subject><subject>Department of Transportation</subject><subject>Department of Veterans Affairs</subject><subject>Department of the Interior</subject><subject>Detention of persons</subject><subject>Disaster relief and insurance</subject><subject>Economic development</subject><subject>Education programs funding</subject><subject>Electric power generation and transmission</subject><subject>Employment and training programs</subject><subject>Energy assistance for the poor and aged</subject><subject>Energy efficiency and conservation</subject><subject>Energy storage, supplies, demand</subject><subject>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)</subject><subject>Environmental health</subject><subject>Executive Office of the President</subject><subject>Executive agency funding and structure</subject><subject>Family planning and birth control</subject><subject>Fires</subject><subject>Food and Drug Administration (FDA)</subject><subject>Foreign aid and international relief</subject><subject>Forests</subject><subject>Government Accountability Office (GAO)</subject><subject>Government Printing Office (GPO)</subject><subject>Government lending and loan guarantees</subject><subject>Hazardous wastes and toxic substances</subject><subject>Health programs administration and funding</subject><subject>Housing and community development funding</subject><subject>Humanities programs funding</subject><subject>Indian social and development programs</subject><subject>Intellectual property</subject><subject>Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information</subject><subject>Iraq</subject><subject>Latin America</subject><subject>Lawyers and legal services</subject><subject>Legal Services Corporation</subject><subject>Library of Congress</subject><subject>Medical research</subject><subject>Middle East</subject><subject>Military civil functions</subject><subject>Military facilities and property</subject><subject>Military medicine</subject><subject>Military operations and strategy</subject><subject>Military personnel and dependents</subject><subject>Military procurement, research, weapons development</subject><subject>Military readiness</subject><subject>Mining</subject><subject>Minority health</subject><subject>Mississippi River</subject><subject>Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers</subject><subject>National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities</subject><subject>National Guard and reserves</subject><subject>Nuclear power</subject><subject>Nuclear weapons</subject><subject>Oil and gas</subject><subject>Palestinians</subject><subject>Radioactive wastes and releases</subject><subject>Research administration and funding</subject><subject>Rural conditions and development</subject><subject>Smithsonian Institution</subject><subject>Terrorism</subject><subject>Transportation programs funding</subject><subject>Water quality</subject><subject>Water resources funding</subject><subject>Wetlands</subject><subject>Women's health</subject></subjects><summary>2/19/2011--Passed House amended. Full-Year Continuing Appropriations Act, 2011 - Makes FY2011 appropriations for the Department of Defense, with some specified items at levels reduced from FY2010 levels. Makes FY2011 appropriations for other federal departments and agencies, with many specified programs at levels reduced from FY2010 levels and funding for certain programs eliminated entirely. (In this summary, references to increases or reductions in funding are stated in the context of FY2010 appropriations.) Division A: Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2011 - Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2011 - Title I: Military Personnel - Appropriates funds for FY2011 for active-duty and reserve personnel in the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, and Air Force (the military departments), and for National Guard personnel in the Army and Air Force. Title II: Operation and Maintenance - Appropriates funds for FY2011 for operation and maintenance (O&amp;M) for the military departments, the defense agencies, the reserve components, and the Army and Air National Guard. Appropriates funds for: (1) the United States Court of Appeals for the Armed Forces; (2) environmental restoration for the military departments, the Department of Defense (DOD), and at formerly used defense sites; (3) overseas humanitarian, disaster, and civic aid; and (4) former Soviet Union threat reduction. Title III: Procurement - Appropriates funds for FY2011 for procurement by the Armed Forces of aircraft, missiles, weapons, tracked combat vehicles, ammunition, shipbuilding and conversion, and other procurement. Appropriates funds for defense-wide procurement. Title IV: Research, Development, Test and Evaluation - Appropriates funds for FY2011 for research, development, test and evaluation (RDT&amp;E) by the Armed Forces and defense agencies. Reduces Navy RDT&amp;E Navy and Air Force funding. (Eliminates funding for the Alternate Engine for the F-35 Joint Strike Fighter.) Appropriates funds for the Director of Operational Test and Evaluation.
Title V: Revolving and Management Funds - Appropriates funds for: (1) the Defense Working Capital Funds; and (2) programs under the National Defense Sealift Fund. Title VI: Other Department of Defense Programs - Appropriates funds for: (1) the Defense Health Program; (2) the destruction of lethal chemical agents and munitions; (3) drug interdiction and counter-drug activities, defense; and (4) the Office of the Inspector General. Title VII: Related Agencies - Appropriates funds for the: (1) Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System Fund; and (2) Intelligence Community Management Account. Title VIII: General Provisions - Specifies authorized, restricted, and prohibited uses of authorized funds. (Sec. 8007) Requires a report from DOD on establishing the baseline for application of FY2011 reprogramming and transfer authorities. (Sec. 8011) Allows for the use of procurement funds for a multiyear contract for Navy MH-60R/S helicopter systems. (Sec. 8013) Prohibits, during FY2011, the management by end strengths of DOD civilian personnel. (Sec. 8023) Authorizes DOD to incur obligations of up to $350 million for DOD military compensation, construction projects, and supplies and services in anticipation of receipts of contributions from the government of Kuwait. (Sec. 8025) Prohibits the use of funds from this Act to establish a new federally funded research and development center (FFRDC). Limits the federal compensation to be paid to FFRDC members or consultants. Prohibits the use of FY2011 funds for new building construction, cost-sharing payments for projects funded by government grants, absorption of contract overruns, or certain charitable contributions. Limits the staff years of technical effort that may be funded for FFRDCs from FY2011 funds. Reduces, by $125 million, the total amount appropriated in this Division for FFRDCs. (Sec. 8026) Provides Buy American requirements with respect to the DOD procurement of carbon, alloy, or armor steel plating. (Sec. 8029) Requires the Secretary of Defense (Secretary) to report to Congress on the amount of DOD purchases from foreign entities in FY2011. (Sec. 8031) Authorizes the Secretary of the Air Force to convey to Indian tribes located in Nevada, Idaho, North Dakota, South Dakota, Montana, Oregon, Minnesota, and Washington relocatable military housing units currently located at Grand Forks, Malmstrom, Mountain Home, Elllsworth, and Minot Air Force Bases that are excess to the needs of the Air Force. Requires the Operation Walking Shield Program to resolve any housing unit conflicts arising after such conveyance. (Sec. 8037) Prohibits the use of funds: (1) by a DOD entity without compliance with the Buy American Act; (2) to establish additional field operating agencies of DOD elements, except for those funded within the National Foreign Intelligence Program and Army agencies established to eliminate, mitigate, or counter the effects of improvised explosive devices or to improve or integrate biometric activities and technologies; (3) for assistance to the Democratic People's Republic of North Korea, unless specifically appropriated for such purpose; and (4) to reduce the civilian medical and medical support personnel assigned to military treatment facilities below the September 30, 2003, level. (Sec. 8041) Rescinds specified funds from various accounts under prior defense appropriations Acts. (Sec. 8046) Prohibits the transfer to any other department or agency, except as specifically provided in an appropriations law, of funds available to DOD or the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) for drug interdiction or counter-drug activities. (Sec. 8050) Prohibits current fiscal year DOD funds from being obligated or expended to transfer to another nation or international organization defense articles or services for use in any United Nations (UN) peacekeeping or peace enforcement operation, or for any other international peacekeeping, peace enforcement, or humanitarian assistance operation, unless Congress is given 15 days' advance notice. (Sec. 8057) Prohibits funds from being used to approve or license the sale of the F-22 advanced tactical fighter to any foreign government. (Sec. 8058) Authorizes the Secretary, on a case-by-case basis, to waive limitations on the procurement of defense items from a foreign country if: (1) the Secretary determines that such limitations would invalidate cooperative or reciprocal trade agreements for the procurement of defense items; and (2) such country does not discriminate against the same or similar defense items procured in the United States for that country. Provides exceptions. (Sec. 8059) Prohibits the use of appropriated funds to support a unit of the security forces of a foreign country if credible information exists that such unit has committed a gross violation of human rights, unless all necessary corrective steps have been taken. Requires the monitoring of such information. Authorizes the Secretary to waive such prohibition under extraordinary circumstances (requiring a report on any such waiver). (Sec. 8065) Authorizes members of the National Guard performing full-time duty to support ground-based elements of the National Ballistic Missile Defense System. (Sec. 8066) Prohibits appropriated funds from being used to transfer to any nongovernmental entity specified armor-piercing ammunition, except to an entity performing demilitarization services for DOD. (Sec. 8067) Authorizes the Chief of the National Guard Bureau to waive payment for the lease of non-excess DOD personal property to certain, youth, social, or fraternal nonprofit organizations. (Sec. 8072) Appropriates funds to DOD for construction and furnishing of additional Fisher Houses for use by family members confronted with the illness or hospitalization of a military beneficiary. (Sec. 8073) Earmarks specified RDT&amp;E funds for the Israeli Cooperative Programs (missile defense). (Sec. 8078) Requires the FY2012 budget to include separate budget justification documents for costs of U.S. Armed Forces' participation in contingency operations for the military personnel, O&amp;M, and procurement accounts. (Sec. 8079) Prohibits funds from being used for RDT&amp;E, procurement, or deployment of nuclear armed interceptors of a missile defense system. (Sec. 8080) Appropriates funds to DOD for four specified grants by the Secretary. (Sec. 8082) Prohibits the availability of funds for integration of foreign intelligence information unless such information has been lawfully collected and processed during the conduct of authorized foreign intelligence activities. (Sec. 8083) Requires reserve members called or ordered to active duty in time of national emergency to be notified in writing of their expected mobilization period. Allows the Secretary to waive such requirement in order to respond to a national security emergency or to meet dire operational requirements. (Sec. 8089) Earmarks specified Navy O&amp;M funds for the Asia Pacific Regional Initiative Program for enabling the Pacific Command to execute Theater Security Cooperation activities such as humanitarian assistance, and the payment of incremental and personnel costs of training and exercising with foreign security forces. (Sec. 8094) Directs the Secretary to create a major force program category for space for DOD's Future Years Defense Program. (Sec. 8095) Requires the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (DNI) to report to the intelligence committees to establish the baseline for application of reprogramming and transfer authorities for FY2011. Prohibits funds provided for the National Intelligence Program from being available for reprogramming or transfer until the report is submitted, unless the DNI certifies to such committees that the reprogramming or transfer is necessary as an emergency requirement. (Sec. 8096) Directs the DNI to submit annually to Congress a future-years intelligence program reflecting estimated expenditures and proposed appropriations included in the President's budget. (Sec. 8098) Requires DOD to continue to report incremental contingency operations costs for Operations New Dawn and Enduring Freedom on a monthly basis. (Sec. 8099) Reduces by $1.983 billion the amount appropriated in title II, to reflect excess cash balances in DOD Working Capital Funds. (Sec. 8100) Authorizes the transfer of specified military department O&amp;M funds to a central fund established for Fisher Houses and Suites. (Sec. 8101) Makes specified Intelligence Community Management Account funds available for transfer by the DNI to other departments and agencies for government-wide information sharing activities. (Sec. 8102) Makes O&amp;M funds available for remittances to the Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Fund. (Sec. 8103) Requires any agency receiving funds appropriated under this Act to post on its public website any report required to be submitted to Congress in this or any other Act, upon a determination by the agency head that doing so will serve the national interest. Provides exceptions when posting the report would compromise national security or for reports containing proprietary information. (Sec. 8105) Provides specific limitations on the use of funds from this Act and certain previous appropriations Acts to begin or announce a competition to award to a contractor, or convert to contractor performance, any functions performed by federal employees pursuant to a study conducted under Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Circular A-76. Provides an exception. (Sec. 8106) Prohibits the use of National Intelligence Program funds from this Act for a mission critical or mission essential business management information technology system not registered with the DNI. Requires the Director of the Business Transformation Office to report semiannually to the defense committees on the results of the Business Transformation Investment Review Board's activities, including certification of compliance with specified procedures prior to a system's approval. (Sec. 8108) Appropriates funds to the Tanker Replacement Transfer Fund for a tanker acquisition program. Requires reports from the Secretary of the Air Force on the use of funds transferred for such purpose. (Sec. 8109) Earmarks specified O&amp;M funds for operations of the integrated Captain James A. Lovell Federal Health Care Center, Illinois. (Sec. 8113) Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2009 to increase the time period during which military personnel may submit claims for retroactive stop-loss special pay compensation from one to two years after the date on which implementing rules for the expedited payment of such claims takes effect. (Sec. 8116) Directs the Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Installations and Environment to conduct energy security pilot projects at DOD facilities. Appropriates funds for such purpose. (Sec. 8118) Requires a report from the Secretary, the Chief of the Air Force Reserve, and the Director of the National Guard Bureau on firefighting aviation assets. Title IX: Overseas Contingency Operations - Appropriates funds for FY2011 for contingency operations directly related to the global war on terrorism, specifically for: (1) military personnel; (2) O&amp;M; (3) the Afghanistan Infrastructure Fund (established by this Act); (4) the Afghanistan Security Forces Fund; (5) the Iraq Security Forces Fund; (6) procurement, including National Guard and Reserve equipment; (7) the Mine Resistant Ambush Protected Vehicle Fund; (8) RDT&amp;E; (9) Defense Working Capital Funds; (10) the Defense Health Program; (11) drug interdiction and counter-drug activities; (12) the Joint Improvised Explosive Device Defeat Fund; and (13) the Office of the Inspector General. Reduces funding for the Mine Resistant Ambush Protected Vehicle Fund. Increases appropriations for: (1) RDT&amp;E; and (2) the Joint Improvised Explosive Device Defeat Fund. (Sec. 9002) Authorizes the Secretary, in the national interest, to transfer up to $4 billion of the amounts made available to DOD in this title between any such authorizations for that fiscal year. Requires prompt congressional notification of each transfer. (Sec. 9004) Authorizes the Secretary to use funds appropriated in this title to purchase motor vehicles for use by military and civilian DOD employees in Iraq and Afghanistan, with a limit of $75,000 per passenger vehicle and $250,000 per each heavy or light armored vehicle. (Sec. 9005) Authorizes the use of specified funds to fund the Commander's Emergency Response Program (urgent humanitarian relief and reconstruction assistance in Iraq and Afghanistan). (Sec. 9006) Allows funds to be used to provide supplies, services, transportation, and other logistical support to coalition forces supporting military and stability operations in Iraq and Afghanistan. Requires quarterly reports from the Secretary regarding such support. (Sec. 9007) Prohibits any funds from being obligated or expended: (1) to establish any military installation or base for providing for the permanent stationing of U.S. Armed Forces in Iraq or Afghanistan; or (2) to exercise U.S. control over any oil resource of Iraq. (Sec. 9008) Prohibits funds from being used in contravention of specified laws enacted or regulations promulgated to implement the United Nations Convention Against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman, or Degrading Treatment or Punishment. (Sec. 9009) Requires quarterly reports from the Secretary on the proposed use of funds from the Iraq Security Forces Fund, the Afghanistan Security Forces Fund, the Afghanistan Infrastructure Fund, and the Pakistan Counterinsurgency Fund on a project-by-project basis. (Sec. 9013) Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of more than 85% of the O&amp;M funds appropriated in this Division until the Secretary reports on contractor employees in the U.S. Central Command. Division B: Full-Year Continuing Appropriations for Fiscal Year 2011 - Makes continuing appropriations for FY2011. Title I: General Provisions - (Sec. 1101) Appropriates FY2011 amounts at the FY2010 level for such continuing operations, projects, or activities as were conducted in FY2010 and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were made available in: (1) the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2010 (P.L. 111-80); (2) the Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2010 (PL 111-85); (3) the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2010 (PL 111-83); (4) the Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2010 (division A of PL 111-88); (5) the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2010 (division A of PL 111-68); (6) the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2010 (P.L 111-117); (7) chapter 1 of title I of the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2010 (PL 111-212), addressing guaranteed loans in the rural housing insurance fund; and (8) the United States Patent and Trademark Office Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2010 (PL 111-224) for the United States Patent and Trademark Office. Provides that this appropriated level shall be the amount appropriated in such appropriations Acts, including transfers and obligation limitations, except for amounts previously designated as emergency requirements and necessary to meet emergency needs pursuant to S.Con.Res. 13, 111th Congress (FY2010 budget resolution). Requires this level to be calculated without regard to any rescission or cancellation of funds or contract authority. (Sec. 1106) Continues through FY2011 appropriations and funds made available and authority granted pursuant to this division, unless otherwise provided for in it or in the applicable appropriations Act. (Sec. 1109) Continues funding at the FY2010 level for entitlements and other mandatory payments whose budget authority was provided in appropriations Acts for FY2010, and for activities under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008. Makes appropriations for the following accounts for advance payments for the first quarter of FY2012: (1) Special Benefits for Disabled Coal Miners, (2) Grants to States for Medicaid, (3) Payments to States for Child Support Enforcement and Family Support Programs, (4) Payments to States for Foster Care and Permanency, and (5) Supplemental Security Income (SSI) Program. (Sec. 1110) Designates as being for contingency operations directly related to the global war on terrorism pursuant to H.Res. 5 (112th Congress), and as emergency requirements pursuant to S.Con.Res. 13, C111th (FY2010 budget resolution), certain amounts incorporated by reference in this division that were previously designated as available for overseas deployments and other activities pursuant to such budget resolution. (Sec. 1111) Denies legal effect to any language specifying an earmark in an FY2010 appropriations Act, or in a committee report or joint explanatory statement accompanying such an Act, with respect to funds appropriated by this division. (Sec. 1112) Prohibits the use of any funds to transfer, release, or assist in the transfer of, or release to or within the United States, its territories, or possessions of Khalid Sheikh Mohammed or any other detainee who: (1) is not a U.S. citizen or a member of the U.S. Armed Forces; and (2) is or was held by DOD on or after June 24, 2009, at the U.S. Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba. (Sec. 1113) Prohibits the use of any funds to transfer any Guantanamo detainee to the custody or effective control of the individual's country of origin, or any other foreign country or entity, unless the DOD Secretary (Secretary in this section), with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, certifies to Congress that the government of the foreign country or the recognized leadership of the foreign entity to which such individual is to be transferred meets specified requirements. Excludes from such prohibition the Secretary's actions taken to transfer such detainees to effectuate a U.S. court order affecting the individual's disposition. Imposes such a prohibition, also, if there is a confirmed case that any Guantanamo detainee at any time after September 11, 2001, was transferred to a foreign country or entity and subsequently engaged in terrorist activity. Authorizes the Secretary to waive the prohibition if such a transfer is in the U.S. national security interests. (Sec. 1114) Bars the use of funds to construct or modify any facility in the United States, its territories, or possessions to house specified individuals for detention or imprisonment in DOD custody or under its effective control. Exempts from this prohibition any modifications of facilities at Guantanamo. (Sec. 1115) Bars the obligation of funds by any covered executive agency in contravention of the certification requirement of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996, as included in revisions to the Federal Acquisition Regulation. (Sec. 1116) Extends through FY2011 the interim final regulations issued by the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) which establish risk-based performance standards for security of chemical facilities and requiring vulnerability assessments and the development and implementation of site security plans for chemical facilities. (Sec. 1117) Continues through FY2011 the Secretary of State's authority to collect a surcharge on applicable fees for each passport application. (Sec. 1118) Extends through FY2011 the authority to use appropriated funds to pay recruitment, relocation, and retention bonuses to members of the Foreign Service, other than chiefs of mission and ambassadors at large, who are on official duty in Iraq, Afghanistan, or Pakistan. Continues through FY2011 the Secretary of State's authority to waive required annuity limitations for reemployed: (1) retired Foreign Service or Civil Service employees who serve in such countries, and (2) annuitants under the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) or the Federal Employees Retirement System (FERS) who serve in certain positions in the Department of State. Extends through FY2011 the authority of the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to waive annuity and pay on reemployment requirements for certain CSRS and FERS annuitants reemployed in specified USAID positions, particularly in Iraq, Pakistan, and Afghanistan, for which there is exceptional difficulty in recruiting or retaining a qualified employee, or when a temporary emergency hiring need exists. (Sec. 1119) Continues through FY2011 the United States Advisory Commission on Public Diplomacy. (Sec. 1120) Extends the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness through the earlier of: (1) September 1, 2011, or (2) the date of the enactment of an authorization Act relating to the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act. Title II: Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies - (Sec. 1201) Decreases appropriations for the Office of the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA). (Sec. 1202) Eliminates appropriations for the Office of Tribal Relations. (Sec. 1203) Decreases appropriations for the Office of the Chief Economist. (Sec. 1204) Decreases appropriations for the National Appeals Division. (Sec. 1205) Decreases appropriations for the Office of Budget and Program Analysis. (Sec. 1206) Eliminates appropriations for the Office of Advocacy and Outreach. (Sec. 1207) Decreases appropriations for the the Chief Information Officer. (Sec. 1208) Decreases appropriations for the Office of the Chief Financial Officer. (Sec. 1209) Decreases appropriations for the Office of Civil Rights. (Sec. 1210) Decreases appropriations for agriculture buildings and facilities, and rental payments. (Sec. 1211) Eliminates appropriations for hazardous materials management. (Sec. 1212) Decreases appropriations for departmental administration. (Sec. 1213) Decreases appropriations for the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Congressional Relations. (Sec. 1214) Decreases appropriations for the Office of Communications. (Sec. 1215) Decreases appropriations for the Office of Inspector General. (Sec. 1216) Decreases appropriations for the Office the General Counsel. (Sec. 1217) Decreases appropriations for the Economic Research Service. (Sec. 1218) Decreases appropriations for the National Agricultural Statistics Service. (Sec. 1219) Decreases appropriations for the National Agricultural Research Service, salaries and expenses. (Sec. 1220) Eliminates appropriations for the National Agricultural Research Service, buildings and facilities. (Sec. 1221) Decreases appropriations for the National Institute of Food and Agriculture, research and education. Eliminates appropriations for competitive grants on improved pest control. (Sec. 1222) Decreases appropriations for the National Institute of Food and Agriculture, extension activities. (Sec. 1223) Decreases appropriations for the National Institute of Food and Agriculture, integrated activities. Eliminates appropriations for: (1) the food safety program; (2) the Food Quality Protection Act risk mitigation program for major food crop systems; (3) the crops affected by Food Quality Protection Act implementation; (4) the methyl bromide transition program; (5) the organic transition program; (6) a competitive international science and education grants program the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977; (7) the critical issues program; and (8) the regional rural development centers program. (Sec. 1224) Decreases appropriations for the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, salaries and expenditures. (Sec. 1225) Decreases appropriations for the the Agricultural Marketing Service, marketing services. (Sec. 1226) Decreases appropriations for the Agricultural Marketing Service, administrative expenses. (Sec. 1227) Eliminates appropriations for the Agricultural Marketing Service, funds for strengthening markets, income, and supply. (Sec. 1228) Decreases appropriations for the Grain Inspection, Packers and Stockyards Administration, salaries and expenses. (Sec. 1229) Increases appropriations for the Grain Inspection, Packers and Stockyards Administration, inspection and weighing services. (Sec. 1230) Decreases appropriations for the Food Safety and Inspection Service. (Sec. 1231) Decreases appropriations for the Farm Service Agency, salaries and expenses. (Sec. 1232) Decreases appropriations for the Farm Service Agency, grassroots source water protection program. (Sec. 1233) Decreases appropriations for the Farm Service Agency, agricultural credit insurance program account and sets forth specified funding reductions and increases within such account. Eliminates appropriations for: (1) Indian tribe land acquisition loans, and (2) Indian highly fractionated land loans. (Sec. 1234) Decreases appropriations for the Risk Management Agency. (Sec. 1235) Decreases appropriations for the Natural Resources Conservation Service, conservation operations. (Sec. 1236) Eliminates appropriations for the Natural Resources Conservation Service, watershed and flood prevention operations. (Sec. 1237) Decreases appropriations for the Natural Resources Conservation Service, watershed rehabilitation program. (Sec. 1238) Eliminates appropriations for the Natural Resources Conservation Service, resource conservation and development. (Sec. 1239) Decreases appropriations for rural development programs, salaries and expenses. (Sec. 1240) Sets forth specified funding reductions and increases for the Rural Housing Service, rural housing insurance fund program account. (Sec. 1241) Appropriates specified funds for the Rural Housing Service, rural housing insurance fund program account. Increases appropriations set aside for direct rural housing loans and eliminates appropriations set aside for unsubsidized rural housing guaranteed loans. (Sec. 1242) Increases appropriations for Rural Housing Service, rural housing insurance fund program account, housing repair loans. (Sec. 1243) Increases appropriations for Rural Housing Service, rural housing insurance fund program account, rental housing repair, rehabilitation, and new construction. (Sec. 1244) Increases appropriations for Rural Housing Service, rural housing insurance fund program account, multifamily housing guaranteed loans. (Sec. 1245) Appropriates funds for self-help housing land development loans and for site development loans. (Sec. 1246) Decreases appropriations for Rural Housing Service, rural housing insurance fund program account, administrative expenses. (Sec. 1247) Decreases appropriations for the Rural Housing Service, rental assistance program. Eliminates appropriations set aside for: (1) debt forgiveness or payments for eligible households, and (2) advances to nonprofit organizations or public agencies for direct costs (other than purchase price) incurred in purchasing projects. (Sec. 1248) Decreases appropriations for the Rural Housing Service, multifamily housing revitalization program account. Sets forth related provisos. (Sec. 1249) Decreases appropriations for the Rural Housing Service, mutual and self-help housing grants. (Sec. 1250) Decreases appropriations for the Rural Housing Service, rural housing assistance grants. (Sec. 1251) Decreases appropriations for the Rural Housing Service, rural community facilities program account. Eliminates appropriations set aside for: (1) a rural community development initiative, (2) facilities in rural communities with extreme unemployment and severe economic depression, and (3) community facilities grants to tribal colleges. (Sec. 1252) Decreases appropriations for the Rural Business-Cooperative Service, rural business program account. Eliminates appropriations set aside for a grant to: (1) a national organization to provide technical assistance for rural transportation, and (2) a national organization to provide technical assistance for tribal rural transportation. (Sec. 1253) Decreases appropriations for the Rural Business-Cooperative Service, rural development loan fund program account, direct loans. (Sec. 1254) States that specified amounts from the Rural Business-Cooperative Service, rural economic development loans program account shall: (1) not be obligated, and (2) are rescinded. (Sec. 1255) Decreases appropriations for the Rural Business-Cooperative Service, rural cooperative development grants. Eliminates appropriations set aside for: (1) a cooperative research agreement with an academic institution to conduct research on the national economic impact of all types of cooperatives, and (2) cooperative agreements for the appropriate technology transfer for rural areas program. (Sec. 1256) Decreases appropriations for the Rural Business-Cooperative Service, rural microenterprise investment program account. (Sec. 1257) Decreases appropriations for the Rural Business-Cooperative Service, rural energy for America program. (Sec. 1258) Decreases appropriations for the Rural Utilities Service, rural water and waste disposal program account. Eliminates appropriations set aside for grants to acquire, construct, or upgrade energy generation, transmission, or distribution facilities serving rural communities with high energy costs. (Sec. 1259) Decreases appropriations for administrative expenses for the Rural Utilities Service rural electrification and telecommunications direct and guaranteed loan programs. (Sec. 1260) Decreases appropriations for the Rural Utilities Service, distance learning, telemedicine, and broadband program. Eliminates appropriations set aside for: (1) noncommercial educational television broadcast stations that serve rural areas and are qualified for community service grants by the Corporation for Public Broadcasting, and (2) certain broadband loans. (Sec. 1261) Eliminates appropriations from the child nutrition programs set aside for: (1) the school community garden pilot program, and (2) the hunger-free communities collaborative grant program and the hunger-free communities infrastructure grant program. (Sec. 1262) Decreases appropriations for the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children (WIC). (Sec. 1263) Decreases appropriations for: (1) disaster assistance, (2) the commodity supplemental food program, (3) emergency food assistance, (4) assistance for nuclear affected islands, and (5) the farmers' market nutrition program. Obligates specified funds for the commodity supplemental food program. Eliminates appropriations set aside for emergency food program infrastructure grants. (Sec. 1264) Decreases appropriations for nutrition programs administration. (Sec. 1265) Decreases appropriations for the Foreign Agricultural Service, salaries and expenses. (Sec. 1266) Decreases appropriations for the Foreign Agricultural Service, food for peace title II grants. (Sec. 1267) Decreases appropriations for the Foreign Agricultural Service, McGovern-Dole international food for education and child nutrition program grants. (Sec. 1268) Increases appropriations for the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), salaries and expenses. Decreases appropriations for: (1) the Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition, (2) the Center for Biologics Evaluation and Research, (3) the Center for Veterinary Medicine, (4) the Center for Devices and Radiological Health and for related field activities in the Office of Regulatory Affairs, (5) the National Center for Toxicological Research, (6) rent and related activities, and (7) other activities. Increases appropriations for: (1) the Center for Drug Evaluation and Research, (2) the Center for Tobacco Products, and (3) payments to the General Services Administration (GSA) for rent. (Sec. 1269) Decreases appropriations for the Commodity Futures Trading Commission. (Sec. 1270) Makes specified set-asides inapplicable to funds appropriated by this division. (Sec. 1271) Makes specified provisos inapplicable to funds appropriated by this division. (Sec. 1272) Eliminates specified appropriations for: (1) a certain construction grant to the National Center for Natural Products Research; (2) construction and interim operations for establishment of an agricultural pest facility in Hawaii; (3) the hunger fellowship program (Congressional Hunger Fellows Act of 2002); (4) a grant to the Kansas Farm Bureau Foundation for work-force initiatives to address rural out-migration; (5) the Farm Service Agency for a pilot program to demonstrate the use of new technologies that increase the rate of growth of reforested hardwood trees on private non-industrial forests lands, enrolling lands on the coast of the Gulf of Mexico that were damaged by Hurricane Katrina in 2005; (6) transportation reimbursement for geographically disadvantaged farmers; and (7) the duram wheat quality program. Eliminates appropriations for: (1) grants to the Wisconsin Department of Agriculture, Trade, and Consumer Protection and a grant to the Vermont Agency of Agriculture, Foods, and Markets; (2) development of a prototype for a national carbon inventory and accounting system for forestry and agriculture; (3) the International Food Protection Training Institute; and (4) the Center for Foodborne Illness Research and Prevention. (Sec. 1273) Makes specified provisions of PL 111-80 inapplicable for FY2011. (Sec. 1274) Exempts specified provisions of PL 111-80 authorizing or requiring certain actions that have been performed before the date of the enactment of this division from reoccurring. (Sec. 1275) Makes certain FY2005 appropriations for rural broadband telecommunication loans available until expended to disburse FY2005-FY2006 obligations. (Sec. 1276) States that with regard to certain programs established or amended by the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008, or programs for which indefinite amounts were provided in such Act to be carried out using Commodity Credit Corporation (CCC) funds: (1) such funds shall be available for salaries and administrative expenses without regard to certain allotment and fund transfer limits, and (2) the use of such funds shall not be considered to be a fund transfer or allotment for purposes of applying such limits. (Sec. 1277) States that with respect to any loan or loan guarantee program administered by the Secretary that has a negative credit subsidy score for FY2011 the program level for the loan or loan guarantee program, for purposes of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990, shall be the FY2010 program level. (Sec. 1278) Increases appropriations for certain environmental quality incentives programs. (Sec. 1279) Increases amounts rescinded for training and education programs under the supplemental nutrition assistance program (formerly known as the food stamp program). (Sec. 1280) Substitutes 2010, 2011, and 2012 for 2009, 2010, and 2011, respectively, in specified provisos of PL 111-80. (Sec. 1281) Prohibits funds from being used to enroll more than 202,218 acres in the wetlands reserve program for FY2011. Reduces the program permanently by 47,782 acres. (Sec. 1282) Limits funding for the conservation stewardship program. (Sec. 1283) Prohibits funds from being used to pay for salaries and expenses for the program providing financial assistance to a local organization for rehabilitation of structural measures built as part of a covered water resource project. Rescinds specified funds for FY2011. (Sec. 1284) Increases funds available in FY2011 to be transferred under the Act of August 24, 1935 to carry out the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act by reducing the maximum amount that triggers such transfer. (Sec. 1285) Limits funding for the biomass crop assistance program. (Sec. 1286) Rescinds specified funds for the Agricultural Research Service, buildings and facilities. (Sec. 1287) Rescinds specified funds for broadband loans. (Sec. 1288) Rescinds specified appropriated discretionary funds for USDA.
Title III: Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies - (Sec. 1301) Decreases Department of Commerce appropriations for: (1) the International Trade Administration for operations and administration; (2) the Minority Business Development Agency for minority business development; and (3) the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) for scientific and technical research and services. (Sec. 1302) Transfers Department of Commerce appropriations from the Bureau of Census, Periodic Censuses and Programs, to the Economic Development Administration, for economic development assistance programs. (Sec. 1304) Increases Department of Commerce appropriations for: ( 1) the National Telecommunications and Information Administration for salaries and expenses; and (2) NIST for industrial technology services. (Sec. 1308) Eliminates appropriations for the Department of Justice (DOJ) for the National Drug Intelligence Center. (Sec. 1309) Decreases DOJ appropriations for: (1) justice information sharing technology; (2) tactical law enforcement wireless communications; (3) legal activities, salaries and expenses; and (4) the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) and U.S. Marshals Service for construction. (Sec. 1311) Increases DOJ appropriations for: (1) the Federal Detention Trustee, and (2) the Federal Prison System (FPS). (Sec. 1316) Decreases appropriations for the Office of Science and Technology Policy. (Sec. 1317) Decreases appropriations for the National Science Foundation (NSF) for: (1) research and related activities, (2) major research equipment and facilities construction, and (3) education and human resources. (Sec. 1320) Decreases Department of Commerce appropriations for the Bureau of the Census for Periodic Censuses and Programs. (Sec. 1321) Eliminates appropriations for: (1) the Department of Commerce, National Telecommunications and Information Administration, for public telecommunications facilities, planning and constructions; (2) DOJ, the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives (ATF) for construction; and (3) DOJ, the Office of Justice Programs, for the Weed and Seed Program Fund. (Sec. 1322) Eliminates appropriations for set-asides in Department of Commerce appropriations for: (1) the International Trade Administration for operations and administration; (2) the Minority Business Development Agency for minority business development; and (3) NIST for scientific and technical research and services. (Sec. 1323) Requires the Department of Commerce, DOJ, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), and NSF to submit spending plans to the House and Senate Committees on Appropriations within 60 days of the enactment of this Act. (Sec. 1324) Eliminates appropriations for a Department of Commerce set-aside for the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) for policy studies related to activities of United Nations Specialized Agencies related to international protection of intellectual property rights. (Sec. 1325) Allocates a specified amount of funds appropriated under this Act to the Department of Commerce for NIST industrial technology services to the Technology Innovation Program. ` (Sec. 1326) Decreases appropriations for construction of research facilities for NIST. Eliminates appropriations for a set-aside for NIST for construction of research science buildings and other projects. (Sec. 1327) Decreases appropriations for the Department of Commerce, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), for operations, research, and facilities and for Pacific Coastal Salmon Recovery. Eliminates appropriations for a set-aside for NOAA projects relating to operations, research, and facilities. (Sec. 1328) Increases appropriations for NOAA procurement, acquisition, and construction. Eliminates appropriations for a set-aside for NOAA projects relating to procurement, acquisition, and construction. (Sec. 1329) Decreases appropriations to DOJ for: (1) the Office of Justice Programs for Justice Assistance and Juvenile Justice Programs; (2) State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance; and (3) Community Oriented Policing Services (COPS). (Sec. 1330) Eliminates appropriations for discretionary grants under the DOJ Office of Justice Programs to improve the functioning of the criminal justice system, to prevent or combat juvenile delinquency, and to assist crime victims. (Sec. 1332) Transfers appropriated amounts from NASA Cross Agency Support to DOJ COPS. Decreases or eliminates appropriations for certain programs under the COPS Program, including grants for armor vests and funding for anti-methamphetamine-related activities and law enforcement technologies and interoperable communications programs. (Sec. 1333) Prohibits funding under this Act for transfers between DOJ appropriations. Limits such transfer authority to DOJ accounts for salaries and expenses for U.S. Attorneys, the U.S. Marshals Services, the FBI, the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA), ATF, and FPS. Treats any such transfer as a reprogramming of funds, subject to compliance with procedures set forth in this Act. (Sec. 1334) Provides that a provision limiting the use of NASA funds for exploration shall not apply to funds appropriated by this Division.. (Sec. 1335) Decreases appropriations for NASA space operations. Eliminates appropriations for operations, production, research, development, and support of the Space Shuttle and the International Space Station and for Space and Flight Support. (Sec. 1336) Decreases appropriations for NASA Cross Agency Support and Construction and Environmental Compliance and Remediation. Eliminates NASA appropriations for set-asides for science research and development activities, exploration research and development activities, and cross agency support activities. (Sec. 1338) Eliminates transfer limitations for NASA aeronautics, space operations, and education. (Sec. 1339) Prohibits the use of appropriated funds by NASA or the Office of Science and Technology Policy to: (1) engage in certain activities with China or any Chinese-owned company unless such activities are specifically authorized by law, and (2) host official Chinese visitors at NASA facilities. (Sec. 1340) Decreases appropriations for payments to the Legal Services Corporation in FY2011. (Sec. 1341) Prohibits the creation or initiation of a new federal program, project, or activity with a reprogramming of funds unless the House and Senate Committees on Appropriations are notified 15 days in advance of such reprogramming. (Sec. 1342) Rescinds funds made available for the Bureau of Census, Periodic Censuses and Programs. (Sec. 1343) Rescinds unobligated funds available for the Emergency Steel, Oil, and Gas Guaranteed Loan Program Account. (Sec. 1344) Rescinds, not later than September 30, 2011, amounts from unobligated balances available to DOJ from prior appropriations for the Office of Justice Programs and for COPS Title IV: Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies - (Sec. 1401) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for specified Army Corps of Engineers-Civil projects in California, Texas, Virginia, West Virginia, Kentucky, and Grand Prairie, Arkansas. (Sec. 1403) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for specified projects conducted by the Department of the Interior, Bureau of Reclamation, Water and Related Resources for: (1) the San Gabriel Basin Restoration Fund (California); (2) St. Mary Storage Unit facilities, Milk River Project, Montana; and (3) the Departmental Irrigation Drainage program for site remediation. (Sec. 1404) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for projects conducted by the Department of Energy (DOE), Energy Programs in connection with: (1) energy efficiency and renewable energy, (2) electricity delivery and energy reliability, (3) Congressionally Directed Nuclear Projects, (4) Congressionally Directed Fossil Energy Projects, (5) Advanced Research Projects Agency - Energy, and (6) Congressionally Directed Science Projects. (Sec. 1409) Prohibits the use of funds made available in this Act for Nuclear Waste Disposal to create a Blue Ribbon Commission to consider all alternatives for nuclear waste disposal. (Sec. 1410) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for specified activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration with respect to: (1) weapons activities, (2) defense nuclear nonproliferation, and (3) the Office of the Administrator. (Sec. 1413) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for Congressionally Directed Defense Environmental Cleanup Projects and Congressionally Directed Other Defense Activities Projects. (Sec. 1415) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for environmental remediation by the Western Area Power Administration at the Basic Substation Site, Henderson, Nevada. (Sec. 1416) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for specified projects or aspects of them conducted by the Army Corps of Engineers-Civil, including projects in the states of Minnesota, Kentucky, Wisconsin, Mississippi, South Dakota, Montana, New Mexico, Iowa, Alaska, Nebraska, California, Florida, Tennessee, Hawaii, North Dakota . Terminates the permission for certain lessees to continue to lease a cabin site in the Charles M. Russell National Wildlife Refuge in Montana even though the lessee does not offer to acquire the site. Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for certain expenditures by the Department of the Interior including: (1) the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation; (2) the Walker Basin Restoration Program (Nevada); (3) grants to implement the Truckee-Carson-Pyramid Lake Water Rights Settlement Act; and (4) implementation of a draft recovery plan for the giant Garter Snake. Terminates all authorities and projects under the Calfed Bay-Delta Authorization Act. Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for a certain water transfer between a certain Friant Division contractor and a certain south-of-Delta CVP agricultural water service contractor with respect to Buffalo Bill Dam and Reservoir, Shoshone Project, Pick-Sloan Missouri Basin Program, Wyoming, under the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992. Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for: (1) federal purchases of light bulbs that are either Energy Star qualified or have the Federal Energy Management Program designation; and (2) the requirement for a full and open competition for the award of certain projects considered congressional earmarks. (Sec. 1417) Appropriates $50 million for the DOE Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy (ARPA-E). (Sec. 1418) Prohibits, unless prior approval is received from congressional appropriations committees, both DOE and the Corps of Engineers, Civil from using funds or authority to initiate or resume any program, project, or activity which has not been funded by Congress (including Requests For Proposals). (Sec. 1419) Prohibits the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) from using funds to conduct closure of adjudicatory functions, technical review, or support activities regarding the Yucca Mountain geologic repository license application until it reverses the Atomic Safety Licensing Board (ASLB) decision LBP-10-11. (In LBP-10-11 the ASLB denied the DOE motion to withdraw its license application seeking authorization to construct a high-level geologic waste repository at Yucca Mountain, Nevada.) (Sec. 1420) Sets forth reduced funding levels for the following Independent Agencies: (1) the Appalachian Regional Commission, (2) the Delta Regional Authority, and (3) the Denali Commission. (Sec. 1423) Eliminates funding for the Northern Border Regional Commission and for the Southeast Crescent Regional Commission. (Sec. 1425) Reduces the total principal amount of loan guarantee commitments under the DOE Title 17 Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Authority Loan Program for eligible projects (other than nuclear power facilities and front-end nuclear facilities). (Sec. 1426) Rescinds from unobligated balances specified amounts: (1) transferred to the Department of the Interior, Bureau of Reclamation, Water and Related Resources, for desert terminal lakes; and (2) available for the Corps of Engineers-Civil, Department of the Army, for the Mississippi River and Tributaries (canceling unobligated balances entirely for the Yazoo Basin, Backwater Pump, Mississippi project). (Sec. 1428) Sets forth the levels, reduced from FY2010 levels, for the following activities of the Corps of Engineers-Civil, Department of the Army: (1) investigations, (2) construction, (3) Mississippi River and tributaries, (4) operation and maintenance, and (5) formerly utilized sites remedial action program. (Sec. 1433) Sets the level for Department of the Interior, Bureau of Reclamation, Water and Related Resources, reduced from the FY2010 level, at $913.5 million (further reduced by $1.897 million). (Sec. 1434) Sets the level, reduced from the FY2010 level, for DOE Energy Programs, Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy. Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for the Weatherization Assistance Program. (Sec. 1435) Sets forth the levels, reduced from FY2010 levels, for the following DOE Energy Programs : (1) Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability, (2) nuclear energy, (3) fossil energy research and development, (4) Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR), (5) the Energy Information Administration, (6) non-defense environmental cleanup, (7) the Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund, (8) science (specifying a limit on the amount for biological and environmental research), (9) departmental administration, and (10) the Advanced Technology Vehicles Manufacturing Loan Program. (Sec. 1445) Sets forth the levels, relative to FY2010 levels, for the following DOE Atomic Energy Defense Activities, National Nuclear Security Administration: (1) weapons (increased), (2) defense nuclear nonproliferation (decreased), (3) naval reactors (increased), and (4) Office of the Administrator (increased). (Sec. 1449) Sets forth the levels, reduced from FY2010 levels, for DOE Environmental and Other Defense Activities for both Defense Environmental Cleanup and specified Other Defense Activities. Transfers specified amounts, also reduced from FY2010 levels, from Defense Environmental Cleanup to the Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund. (Sec. 1451) Rescinds from unobligated balances from prior year appropriations specified amounts designated for Corps of Engineers-Civil, Department of the Army, Construction. (Sec. 1452) Rescinds from unobligated balances from prior year appropriations specified amounts designated for the following DOE Energy Programs: (1) energy efficiency and renewable energy, (2) electricity delivery and energy reliability, (3) nuclear energy, (4) fossil energy research and development, (5) naval petroleum and oil shale reserves, (6) clean coal technology, (7) SPR, (8) the Energy Information Administration, (9) non-defense environmental cleanup, (10) the Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund, (11) science, (12) nuclear waste disposal, and (13) departmental administration. (Sec. 1465) Rescinds from unobligated balances from prior year appropriations specified amounts designated for DOE Atomic Energy Defense Activities, National Nuclear Security Administration for: (1) defense nuclear nonproliferation, (2) naval reactors, and (3) the Office of the Administrator. (Sec. 1468) Rescinds from unobligated balances from prior year appropriations specified amounts designated for DOE Environmental and Other Defense Activities for: (1) defense environmental cleanup, and (2) specified other defense activities. (Sec. 1470) Rescinds specified amounts from unobligated balances from prior year appropriations available for the following Independent Agencies: (1) the Delta Regional Authority, and (2) the Denali Commission. (Sec. 1472) Requires the following entities to submit to congressional appropriations committees a spending, expenditure, or operating plan for FY2011 at a level of detail below the account level: (1) DOE, (2) the Corps of Engineers, Civil, (3) the NRC, and (4) the Bureau of Reclamation. (Sec. 1473) Declares that no rescission made in this title shall apply to any amount previously designated by Congress as an emergency requirement. (Sec. 1474) Prohibits the use of any appropriations for Energy and Water Development, except those under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009, to pay employment or termination costs of any DOE employee appointed, employed, or retained using funds provided by the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (or whose functions or operations are funded under such law). (Sec. 1475) Prohibits the use of appropriations made available by this Act to implement specified "Reasonable and Prudent Action Components" described in the biological opinion for the operations of the Central Valley Project and the California State Water Project issued by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, dated December 15, 2008, and June 4, 2009, respectively. Prohibits the use of appropriations made available by this Act to implement the San Joaquin River Restoration Settlement under the San Joaquin River Restoration Settlement Act, including: (1) the Stipulation of Settlement dated September 13, 2006, in Natural Resources Defense Council et. Al. V. Kirk Rogers, et. al.; (2) the acquisition and disposal of property and title to facilities; (3) appropriations for both implementation and creation of a San Joaquin River Restoration Fund; and (4) reintroduction into the San Joaquin River of the California Central Valley Spring Run Chinook salmon. Title V: Financial Services and General Government - (Sec. 1501) Decreases appropriations to the Department of the Treasury for salaries and/or expenses for: (1) Department-wide Systems and Capital Investment Programs; (2) the Office of Inspector General; (3) the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network; (4) the Financial Management Service; (5) the Bureau of Public Debt; (6) the Alcohol and Tobacco Tax and Trade Bureau; and (7) the Internal Revenue Service (IRS), including for Tax Payer Service and Operations Support. (Sec. 1504) Increases appropriations for salaries and/or expenses for: (1) the Special Inspector General for the Troubled Asset Relief Program (TARP), (2) the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund Program Account (financial assistance, technical assistance, training outreach programs, and administrative expenses), (3) terrorism and financial intelligence activities, and (4) IRS Enforcement. (Sec. 1508) Rescinds specified unobligated balances available for the Treasury Forfeiture Fund. (Sec. 1514) Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer specified funds appropriated for Enforcement and Operations Support to Business Systems Modernization, upon approval of the congressional appropriations committees. (Sec. 1516) Prohibits IRS use of funds made available by this division to implement or enforce any amendment made to the Internal Revenue Code (relating to information at source) by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) (applying to corporations certain reporting requirements for payments of $600 or more to persons engaged in a trade or business). (Sec. 1517) Prohibits during FY2011: (1) the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve from transferring more than $80 million to the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection (BCFP) for activities authorized under the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, or (2) the BCFP from obligating more than such amount for such activities. (Sec. 1518) Decreases appropriations to the Executive Office of the President and Funds Appropriated to the President, White House for salaries and/or expenses for: (1) repair and restoration, (2) the Council of Economic Advisors, (3) the National Security Council, (4) the Office of Administration, (5) the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), (6) the Office of National Drug Control Policy (including policy research and evaluation as well as other federal drug control programs), (7) the Special Assistance to the President, and (8) the Official Residence of the Vice President. (Sec. 1521) Rescinds specified unobligated balances available for: (1) the Counterdrug Technology Assessment Center, (2) the Office of National Drug Control Policy, and (3) the Partnership Fund for Program Integrity Innovation. (Sec. 1528) Eliminates appropriations for: (1) the Counterdrug Technology Assessment Center; (2) unanticipated needs of the President in furtherance of the national interest, security, or defense; and (3) the Partnership Fund for Program Integrity Innovation. (Sec. 1535) Prohibits the use of funds appropriated for an Assistant to the President for Energy and Climate Change or the Director of the Office of Health Care Reform, or any substantially similar positions. (Sec. 1537) Decreases appropriations for salaries and/or expenses for: (1) the U.S. Supreme Court; (2) the Courts of Appeals, District Courts, and Other Judicial Services; (3) fees of Jurors and Commissioners; (4) the Administrative Office of the U.S. Courts; (5) the Federal Judicial Center; and (6) the U.S. Sentencing Commission (including a specified rescission of unobligated balances). (Sec. 1543) Increases FY2011 appropriations for court security. (Sec. 1544) Decreases appropriations transferred from the Vaccine Injury Compensation Trust Fund to the U.S. Court of Federal Claims for expenses associated with processing cases under the National Childhood Vaccine Injury Act of 1986. (Sec. 1546) Amends the Judicial Improvement Act of 1990 to prohibit the filling of the first vacancy in the office of district judge in the district of Kansas occurring 20 (currently, 19) years or more after the confirmation date of the judge named to fill the temporary judgeship. (Sec. 1547) Decreases appropriations for the District of Columbia federal payment for: (1) the District of Columbia courts (including capital improvements), (2) school improvement (including a reduction for D.C. Public Schools but no change in the $20 million to expand quality public charter schools), (3) the D.C. Water and Sewer Authority, (4) the Criminal Justice Coordinating Council, (5) housing for the homeless, and (6) capitol improvement. (Sec. 1548) Increases appropriations for opportunity scholarships for D.C. students. Eliminates appropriations for salaries and/or expenses for testing of students to determine and compare academic performance of schools enrolling students participating in the scholarship program. Applies the authority and conditions provided in the District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2010 regarding the scholarship program to the funds made available under this division. Waives the limitation of opportunity scholarships to those who received them in the 2009-2010 school year. Makes funds available for such scholarships to students regardless of whether they received any in a prior school year. Requires the Secretary of Education to ensure that site inspections of participating schools are conducted annually (instead of at least twice annually). (Sec. 1550) Eliminates appropriations for the federal payment to the Office of the Chief Financial Officer for the District of Columbia, for a consolidated bioterrorism and forensics laboratory, and for youth services. (Sec. 1555) Authorizes the District to expend local funds for programs and activities, subject to specified conditions. (Sec. 1556) Decreases appropriations for salaries and/or expenses for the: (1) Christopher Columbus Fellowship Foundation; (2) General Service Administration (GSA) for government-wide policy; (3) Federal Labor Relations Authority (FLRA); (4) GSA Electronic Government Fund; (5) GSA Federal Citizen Services; (6) Federal Election Commission (FEC); (7) Federal Trade Commission (FTC); (8) Morris K. Udall and Stewart Udall Trust Fund; (9) the Community Development Revolving Loan Fund of the National Credit Union Administration (NCUA); (10) Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board; (11) Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC), with a reduced amount available for the Virginia Graeme Baker Pool and Spa Safety Act grant program (and rescinding a specified amount of unobligated balances for the program); (12) Election Assistance Commission (EAC) (but with no funds for election reform programs); (13) GSA operating expenses (but with no funds for an authorized payment to the Oklahoma City National Memorial Foundation); and (14) National Archives and Records Administration (NARA), including electronic records archives, repairs and restoration, and the grants program of the National Historical Publications and Records Commission. (Sec. 1559) Increases appropriations for salaries and/or expenses for the: (1) Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC), Office of the Inspector General; and (2) the U.S. Tax Court. (Sec. 1570) Transfers specified EAC funds to the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) for certain election reform activities under the Help America Vote Act of 2002. Eliminates appropriations for the Help America Vote College Program and the competitive grant program to support community involvement in student and parent mock elections. (Sec. 1571) Rescinds unobligated balances available to the EAC for election reform programs. (Sec. 1572) Decreases the aggregate amount of new obligational authority for the GSA Federal Building Fund. Eliminates appropriations for GSA construction and acquisition. Allocates certain GSA appropriations for fire and life safety programs. (Sec. 1578) Rescinds specified unobligated balances available for NARA repairs and restoration. Derives such balances from amounts made available for a new regional archives and records facility in Anchorage, Alaska. (Sec. 1579) Decreases appropriations for salaries and/or expenses for: (1) the Merit Systems Protection Board; (2) the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), including the Office of Inspector General; (3) the Office of Special Counsel; (4) the Small Business Administration (SBA); (5) the payment to the U.S. Postal Service Fund; (6) the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) (but with none derived from prior year unobligated balances from funds previously appropriated to the SEC); and (7) the Selective Service System. (Sec. 1583) Rescinds specified unobligated balances available for the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board. (Sec. 1584) Eliminates appropriations earmarked for SBA initiatives related to small business development and entrepreneurship, including certain programmatic and construction activities. (Sec. 1589) Increases appropriations to the U.S. Tax Court by a specified amount to be allocated for security improvements. (Sec. 1590) Prohibits the expenditure of any funds appropriated by this division (currently, only federal funds) for abortions, except where the mother's life would be endangered if the fetus were carried to term, or in cases of rape or incest. (Sec. 1591) Prohibits the use of funds contained in this division for any program of distributing sterile needles or syringes for the hypodermic injection of any illegal drug. Title VI: Homeland Security - (Sec. 1601) Directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to submit to the Senate and House Appropriations Committees an expenditure plan for FY2011 that displays the level of funding by program, project, and activity consistent with the table of detailed funding recommendations contained in the joint explanatory statement accompanying the DHS Appropriations Act, 2010. (Sec. 1602) Decreases appropriations for DHS for FY2011 for the Office of the Secretary and Executive Management, the Undersecretary for Management, and the Chief Information Officer. (Sec. 1605) Eliminates appropriations for the Office of the Federal Coordinator for Gulf Coast Rebuilding. (Sec. 1606) Increases appropriations to U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) for salaries and expenses, but decreases funding for: (1) automation modernization; (2) border security fencing, infrastructure, and technology; (3) air and marine interdiction; and (4) construction and facilities management. Requires the Border Patrol to maintain an active duty presence of not fewer than 20,500 full-time equivalent agents throughout FY2011. (Sec. 1611) Increases appropriations to U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) for salaries and expenses, but decreases funding for automation modernization and eliminates appropriations for construction. Requires ICE to maintain not fewer than 33,400 detention beds throughout FY2011. (Sec. 1614) Decreases appropriations for the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) for aviation security, surface transportation security, transportation threat assessment and credentialing, and transportation security support. Increases appropriations for aviation security direction and enforcement and for Federal Air Marshals. Prohibits TSA funds from being used to exceed a staffing level of 46,000 full-time equivalent screeners. Directs the Secretary of DHS to report on: (1) DHS's efforts to develop more advanced, integrated, and effective passenger screening technologies at the lowest possible costs; and (2) how TSA is deploying its existing screener workforce in the most cost-effective manner. Requires funding for intelligence and international programs to be no less than the level provided for FY2010. Limits appropriations for headquarters administration and information technology. (Sec. 1619) Increases appropriations for the Coast Guard for operating expenses. Decreases appropriations for acquisition, construction, and improvements, except that allocations are increased for: (1) shore facilities and aids to navigation facilities; (2) personnel compensation, benefits, and related costs; and (3) the Integrated Deepwater Systems program, for which funding for aircraft is decreased and funding for surface ships is increased. Eliminates appropriations for alteration of bridges. (Sec. 1622) Increases appropriations for the United States Secret Service. (Sec. 1623) Decreases appropriations for the National Protection and Programs Directorate for management and administration, infrastructure protection and information security, and United States Visitor and Immigrant Status Indicator Technology (US-VISIT) (Sec. 1626) Decreases appropriations for the Office of Health Affairs. (Sec. 1627) Decreases appropriations for the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) for (1) management and administration, including the elimination of funding for capital improvements at the Mount Weather Emergency Operations Center); (2) state and local programs, including the elimination of funding for Regional Catastrophic Preparedness Grants, Buffer Zone Protection Grants, the Interoperable Emergency Communications Grant Program, grants for Emergency Operations Centers, the Center for Counterterrorism and Cyber Crime at Norwich University, and the Rural Domestic Preparedness Consortium at Eastern Kentucky University; (3) Emergency Management Performance Grants; (4) the National Predisaster Mitigation Fund; and (5) Emergency Food and Shelter. Increases appropriations for Disaster Relief. (Sec. 1632) Limits the availability of funds from the National Flood Insurance Fund for for operating expenses and agents' commissions and taxes, but increases the level of funding for activities under such Act and the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973. (Sec. 1635) Increases appropriations for United States Citizenship and Immigration Services (CIS), including for processing applications for asylum and refugee status, but decreases appropriations for the E-Verify Program. Prohibits the use of funds for grants for immigrant integration. (Sec. 1636) Decreases appropriations for the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center for acquisitions, construction, improvements, and related expenses. (Sec. 1637) Decreases appropriations for Science and Technology for: (1) management and administration; and (2) research, development, acquisition, and operations, including the elimination of the allocation for the National Bio- and Agro-defense Facility. (Sec. 1639) Decreases appropriations for the Domestic Nuclear Detection Office for management and administration and for research, development, and operations. (Sec. 1641) Requires DHS, upon completion of 50% of design planning for the National Bio- and Agro-Defense Facility, to submit to the Appropriations Committees a revised site-specific biosafety and biosecurity mitigation risk assessment that describes how to significantly reduce risks of conducting essential research and diagnostic testing at the Facility and addresses shortcomings identified in the National Academy of Sciences' evaluation of the initial site-specific biosafety and biosecurity mitigation risk assessment. Directs DHS to contract with the Academy to evaluate the adequacy and validity of the risk assessment (Sec. 1644) Extends through FY2011 the authority of: (1) the Secretary of Defense to carry out specified research and development projects; and (2) the Secret Service to use specified funds for undercover investigative operations. (Sec. 1646) Rescinds, from funds transferred to DHS when it was created, specified funds for Operations, the Violent Crime Reduction Program, CBP salaries and expenses, and the Office for Domestic Preparedness. (Sec. 1647) Rescinds specified amounts from unobligated balances: (1) made available or appropriated to DHS for specified programs and accounts; and (2) made available in the Department of the Treasury Forfeiture Fund. Title VII: Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies - (Sec. 1701) Decreases appropriations for the Department of Interior's Bureau of Land Management (BLM) for management of lands and resources, construction activities, and land acquisition. (Sec. 1704) Decreases appropriations to the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS) for resource management, construction activities, land acquisition, the Cooperative Endangered Species Conservation Fund, the Neotropical Migratory Bird Conservation Act, and the Multinational Species Conservation Fund. Rescinds all remaining unobligated amounts from prior year appropriations for the Landowner Incentive Program. Eliminates appropriations to the USFWS for the Idaho Salmon and Clearwater River Basins Habitat Account, the North American Wetlands Conservation Fund, and State and Tribal Wildlife Grants. (Sec. 1713) Requires the Secretary of the Interior to reissue the final rule published on April 2, 2009, concerning: (1) identifying Northern Rocky Mountain (NRM) Population of gray wolf as a distinct population segment (DPS); and (2) removing the gray wolf within the NRM DPS boundaries in Montana and Idaho from the endangered and threatened wildlife list under the Endangered Species Act. Prohibits such reissuance from being subject to judicial review. (Sec. 1714) Decreases appropriations to the National Park Service (NPS) for operation of the National Park System, national recreation and preservation, the Historic Preservation Fund, construction activities, and expenses necessary to carry out the Land and Water Conservation Act of 1965, including for acquisition of lands or waters. Eliminates appropriations for Park Partnership Project Grants, Preserve America grants, Save America's Treasures grants, the state assistance program for land acquisition, and American Battlefield Protection Program grants. Rescinds specified amounts of unobligated balances of amounts made available for: (1) the project at Cape Hatteras National Seashore in North Carolina; and (2) the project at Blue Ridge Parkway in North Carolina. (Sec. 1719) Rescinds the contract authority provided for FY2011 for acquiring lands and waters for recreational areas in the National Park System, wilderness areas and other specified areas in the National Forest System, and certain land in the National Wildlife Refuge System. (Sec. 1721) Decreases appropriations to the Department of Interior's United States Geological Survey (USGS) for surveys, investigations, and research. Increases the amount that shall remain available until expended for satellite operations. (Sec. 1722) Increases appropriations to the Department of Interior's Minerals Management Service (MMS) for royalty and offshore minerals management and oil spill research. (Sec. 1724) Requires the Secretary, in implementing a reorganization of the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, Regulation, and Enforcement, to conform with Congress's reprograming guidelines when establishing accounts and transferring funds among offices and bureaus affected. (Sec. 1725) Increases appropriations to the Department of Interior's Bureau of Indian Affairs for operations of Indian Programs, including increases for school operations costs of BIA-funded schools and other education programs. Decreases appropriations for construction activities and Indian Land and Water Claim Settlements. Eliminates appropriations for BIA's Pueblo of Isleta Natural Resources Restoration Fund. (Sec. 1728) Decreases appropriations to the Department of the Interior for: (1) management of the Department, (2) assistance to territories, (3) the Office of the Solicitor, (4) the Office of Inspector General, and (5) the Office of the Special Trustee for American Indians. Increases appropriations for the Compacts of Free Association for the Republic of Palau and the Government of the Republic of the Marshall Islands and the Federated States of Micronesia. (Sec. 1734) Decreases appropriations to the Department of Interior for wildland fire management, the Natural Resource Damage Assessment Fund, the Working Capital Fund. (Sec. 1737) Decreases appropriations to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) for: (1) science and technology; (2) environmental programs and management, including geographic programs; (3) the Hazardous Substance Superfund; and (4) leaking underground storage tank cleanup activities. Decreases appropriations for state and tribal assistance grants for environmental programs and infrastructure assistance, including: (1) the Clean Water State Revolving Funds; (2) the Drinking Water State Revolving Funds; (3) grants to Alaska to address the drinking water and wastewater infrastructure needs of rural and Alaska Native Villages; (4) brownfields revitalization funding; (5) grants for diesel emissions reduction; (6) grants for media pollution prevention, control and abatement and related activities; and (7) grants for particulate matter monitoring and data collection activities. Eliminates appropriations for: (1) planning and design of high-performance green building to consolidate EPA's facilities in Las Vegas, Nevada; (2) activities in connection with the construction of high priority water and wastewater facilities near the U.S.-Mexico Border; (3) making special project grants and technical corrections to prior-year grants for the construction of drinking water, wastewater and storm water infrastructure and for water quality protection; (4) targeted airshed grants; and (5) grants to communities to develop plans and demonstrate and implement projects which reduce greenhouse gas emissions. (Sec. 1744) Decreases the amount of appropriated funds that the EPA Administrator is authorized to transfer from the Great Lakes Initiative to federal agencies to support such Initiative. (Sec. 1745) Rescinds a specified amount of unobligated balances available for EPA. (Sec. 1746) Prohibits funds made available to EPA under this Act or any other Act from being: (1) expended for the purpose of enforcing or promulgating any regulation (except for regulations with respect to emission standards for new motor vehicles or new motor vehicle engines under the Clean Air Act) or order, taking action relating to, or denying approval of state implementation plans or permits because of the emissions of greenhouse gases due to concerns regarding possible climate change; or (2) used by EPA to implement, administer, or enforce a change to a rule or guidance document pertaining to the definition of waters under the jurisdiction of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act). (Sec. 1748) Decreases appropriations to the Department of Agriculture (USDA) for the Forest Service for forest and rangeland research, state and private forestry, the National Forest System, capital improvement and maintenance, land acquisition, and wildland fire management. Rescinds a specified amount of unobligated balances available in the FLAME Wildfire Suppression Reserve Fund. (Sec. 1754) Extends the authority of the Secretary of Agriculture, until September 30, 2011, to permit the State Forester of Utah to perform forest, rangeland, and watershed restoration services on National Forest System lands in Utah. (Sec. 1755) Increases appropriations to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) for the Indian Health Service for Indian health services. Decreases appropriations to the Service for Indian health facilities. (Sec. 1757) Decreases appropriations for: (1) the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences, (2) the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry for toxic substances and environmental public health, (3) the President's Council on Environmental Quality (CEQ) and the Office of Environmental Quality; and (4) the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board. (Sec. 1760) Eliminates appropriations for a National Academy of Sciences study of the use and storage of methyl isocyanate. (Sec. 1761) Decreases appropriations to the Smithsonian Institution for salaries and expenses and for repair, revitalization, and alteration of facilities. Eliminates appropriations for the Smithsonian's Legacy Fund. (Sec. 1764) Decreases appropriations to the National Gallery of Art for repair, restoration, and renovation of buildings. Increases appropriations for repairing the National Gallery's East Building facade. (Sec. 1765) Decreases appropriations to the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts. Eliminates appropriations for a program to train arts managers throughout the United States. (Sec. 1767) Decreases appropriations for the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, the National Foundation on the Arts, and the National Endowment for the Humanities. (Sec. 1770) Eliminates appropriations for the National Arts and Cultural Affairs, the Presidio Trust Fund, and the Dwight D. Eisenhower Memorial Commission. (Sec. 1775) Eliminates funding to EPA for transfer to the Department of the Navy for clean-up activities at Treasure Island Naval Station - Hunters Point Annex, California. (Sec. 1776) Prohibits the Secretary of Agriculture from using any funds made available by this Act or any other Act to increase recreation residence user fees by more than 25% in 2011. (Sec. 1777) Requires the Department of the Interior, EPA, the Forest Service, the Indian Health Service, the Council on Environmental Quality, the Smithsonian Institution, the National Gallery of Art, the National Endowment for the Arts, and the National Endowment for the Humanities to submit a spending, expenditure, or operating plan for FY2011 at a level of detail below the account level. (Sec. 1778) Prohibits any funds from being used to implement, administer, or enforce Secretarial Order No. 3310 issued by the Secretary of the Interior on December 22, 2010, which directs the BLM to designate appropriate areas as wild lands and to manage them to protect their wilderness characteristics. Title VIII: Labor, Health and Human Services, Education, and Related Agencies - (Sec. 1801) Decreases appropriations for training and employment services in the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor. Eliminates appropriations for: (1) grants to states for adult employment and training activities, youth activities, and dislocated worker employment and training activities; (2) YouthBuild activities for disadvantaged youth; (3) ex-offender job training and placement programs; (4) activities that prepare workers for careers in energy efficiency and renewable energy; (5) the Career Pathways Innovation Fund; and (6) the Workforce Data Quality Initiative. Decreases appropriations for pilots, demonstrations, and research to address national employment and training programs. Eliminates funding for projects of specific entities that include job training initiatives and training for green jobs. Rescinds appropriations for dislocated worker employment and training activities. (Sec. 1802) Rescinds appropriations for the Office of Job Corps in the Department of Labor. Prohibits funds made available by this division or any prior Act from being used to initiate a competition for any new Job Corps center not previously approved by the Secretary of Labor as a Job Corps center through a competitive selection process. (Sec. 1803) Rescinds appropriations for the Dislocated Workers Assistance National Reserve. (Sec. 1804) Rescinds appropriations for the evaluation of national activities in the Training and Employment Services of the Employment and Training Administration. (Sec. 1805) Decreases appropriations for community service employment programs for low-income Americans over the age of 55. (Sec. 1806) Decreases appropriations for salaries and expenses in the Mine Safety and Health Administration. Requires the Secretary of Labor to transfer funds for activities related to the Department of Labor's caseload before the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission. Eliminates appropriations to continue the project with the United Mine Workers of America for classroom and simulated rescue training for mine rescue teams. (Sec. 1807) Decreases appropriations to the Department of Labor for departmental management. Eliminates appropriations for the United States' contribution to the International Labour Organization's International Program on the Elimination of Child Labor. (Sec. 1808) Rescinds appropriations from the Department of Labor's Working Capital Fund to be derived solely from amounts available in the Investment in Reinvention Fund. (Sec. 1809) Decreases appropriations to the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) in the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) for health resources and services. Increases appropriations for liability coverage for health centers. Eliminates appropriations for voluntary family planning projects. Designates appropriations for health professions programs. Eliminates allocations for: (1) the Denali Commission, (2) the Delta Health Initiative, (3) patient navigators, (4) construction and renovation of health care and other facilities, and (5) state health access grants to expand access to affordable health coverage for the uninsured. Eliminates funding for projects of specific entities, including programs related to health facilities and equipment and health professionals training. Makes inapplicable provisions which require states to maintain and not decrease funds for maternal and childhood block grants. Removes requirement that Secretary of HHS transfer funds from the Community Health Center Fund to increase funding for community health centers and the National Health Service Corps over the FY2008 level. (Sec. 1810) Decreases appropriations for disease control, research and training in the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Prohibits funds from being made available for the acquisition of real property, equipment, construction, renovation of CDC facilities. Decreases appropriations for the Strategic National Stockpile. Eliminates funding for projects of specific entities, including emergency preparedness planning and youth and family wellness programs. Removes a requirement that the Secretary of HHS increase funding over FY2008 levels for prevention, wellness, and public health activities authorized under the Public Health Service Act (PHSA). (Sec. 1811) Decreases appropriations for the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NAID). Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to transfer funds from the accounts of other NIH institutes, centers, and the Office of the Director accounts to NAID. Eliminates transfer from Department of Homeland Security (DHS) for necessary expenses for securing medical countermeasures against biological terror attacks. Eliminates appropriations for International Assistance Programs "Global Fund to Fight HIV/AIDS, Malaria, and Tuberculosis." (Sec. 1812) Decreases appropriations to NIH through a pro rata reduction in all of the Institutes, Centers, and Office of the Director accounts within NIH. Requires the Director of NIH to ensure that the average of the total cost of Competing Research Project Grants for all of the Institutes, Centers, and Office of the Director accounts during FY2011 does not exceed a specified cap. (Sec. 1813) Decreases appropriations for the study of, construction of, renovation of, and acquisition of equipment for, facilities of or used by NIH, including the acquisition of real property. (Sec. 1814) Decreases appropriations for the Substance Abuse and Mental Services Administration. Eliminates funding for projects of specific entities or funds for specific projects, including behavioral health services and suicide prevention programs for adolescents. Removes a requirement that funds be expended to reimburse the General Services Administration (GSA) for environmental testing and remediation on the federally owned facilities at St. Elizabeths Hospital. (Sec. 1815) Decreases appropriations for health care research and quality in the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ). (Sec. 1816) Decreases appropriations for program management in the Center for Medicare and Medicaid (CMS). Eliminates appropriations for the Research, Demonstration, and Evaluation program. Decreases appropriations for CMS Medicare contracting reform activities. Eliminates funding for projects of specific entities, including uncompensated care to treat uninsured or underinsured patients and primary care workforce recruitment. (Sec. 1817) Decreases appropriations for the Low Income Home Energy Assistance program to meet the additional home energy assistance needs of one or more states rising from a natural disaster or other emergency in the Administration for Children and Families. (Sec. 1818) Decreases appropriations to the Administration for Children and Families for payments to states for the Child Care and Development Block Grant. Prohibits any funds from being used for the Child Care Aware toll-free hotline. (Sec. 1819) Decreases appropriations for children and families services programs in the Administration of Children and Families (ACF). Decreases appropriations for making payments under the Community Service Block Grant Act and under the Head Start Act. Eliminates: (1) appropriations for the National Commission on Children and Disasters to carry out the Commission's duties; and (2) funding for projects of specific entities, including gang prevention and intervention and programs for homeless children. (Sec. 1820) Decreases appropriations for aging services programs in the Administration on Aging. Eliminates funding for projects of specific entities, including elder abuse prevention and a program to provide medical products and services to seniors. Prohibits funds under this Act from being used to carry out chronic disease self-management activity grants, except as necessary to administer grants awarded prior to the date of enactment of this division. (Sec. 1821) Decreases appropriations for general departmental management of HHS. Eliminates: (1) appropriations to assist Afghanistan in the development of maternal and child health clinics, (2) appropriations for making competitive contracts and grants to public and private entities to fund medically accurate and age appropriate programs that reduce teen pregnancy, and (3) funding for projects of specific entities, including technical assistance to human services transportation providers on Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) requirements and health information technology evaluation. (Sec. 1822) Increases appropriations for expenses necessary to support activities related to countering potential biological, nuclear, radiological, chemical, and cybersecurity threats to civilian populations, for other public health emergencies, and to pay for the procurement of security countermeasures. Decreases appropriations to respond to an influenza pandemic and prohibits any of such funds from being available past September 30, 2011. Decreases appropriations for expenses necessary for fit-out and other costs related to a competitive lease procurement to renovate or replace the existing headquarters building for Public Health Service agencies and other components of HHS. Permits funds available for the procurement of medical countermeasures to be used to support advanced research and development and other administrative expenses under the Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority. Prohibits any funds from being made available to the United States Postal Service (USPS) for the delivery of medical countermeasures. (Sec. 1823) Rescinds specified appropriations to the Public Health and Social Services Emergency Fund. (Sec. 1824) Decreases appropriations to the Department of Education for: (1) education for the disadvantaged; (2) school improvement programs; (3) innovation and improvement activities; (4) safe schools and citizenship education; (5) special education; (6) rehabilitation services and disability research; (7) career, technical, and adult education; (8) student financial assistance; (9) higher education; and (10) the Institute of Education Sciences. Rescinds certain unobligated balances for education for the disadvantaged. (Sec. 1831) Reduces the maximum individual Pell Grant amount from $4,860 during award year 2010-2011 to $4,015 during award year 2011-2012. (Sec. 1835) Eliminates appropriations for the operating expenses of the Corporation for National and Community Service. Reduces its appropriations for salaries and expenses, and the National Service Trust. (Sec. 1838) Eliminates appropriations for the Corporation for Public Broadcasting, and rescinds a specified unobligated balance. (Sec. 1839) Decreases appropriations to the Institute of Museum and Library Services. (Sec. 1840) Increases appropriations for salaries and expenses of the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission. (Sec. 1841) Decreases appropriations for salaries and expenses of the National Labor Relations Board. (Sec. 1842) Decreases appropriations for Railroad Retirement Board to the Dual Benefits Payment Account. (Sec. 1843) Increases payments to the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund. Allows such payments to be used for transfers for certain benefits for veterans.. (Sec. 1844) Decreases appropriation for administrative expenses of the Social Security Administration (SSA). (Sec. 1845) Increases appropriations to SSA for the Supplemental Security Income Program. (Sec. 1846) Rescinds appropriations to SSA for investment in information technology and telecommunications hardware and software infrastructure. (Sec. 1847) Prohibits funds appropriated in this Act from being used to carry out any program for distributing sterile needles or syringes for the hypodermic injection of any illegal drug. (Sec. 1848) Decreases appropriations for salaries and expenses in the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA). Decreases the amount available for grants to states for occupational safety and health grants. (Sec. 1849) Decreases appropriations to the Office of the Director in NIH. Decreases appropriations to the Common Fund under the PHSA. (Sec. 1850) Decreases appropriations to NIH, through a pro rata reduction in all of the Institutes, Centers, and Office of the Director accounts within NIH. Requires the Director of NIH to ensure that at least 9,000 new competing research grants are awarded in FY2011 from all Institutes, Centers, and Office of the Director accounts. (Sec. 1851) Rescinds appropriations for Refugee and Entrant Assistance in ACF. Title IX: Legislative Branch - (Sec. 1901) Decreases appropriations to the House of Representatives for: (1) salaries and/or expenses of the House leadership offices, committees (including the Committee on Appropriations), officers and employees; (2) allowances and expenses; and (3) Members' representational allowances. (Sec. 1904) Prohibits the use of funds appropriated for committees and their employees for committee room upgrading. (Sec. 1907) Eliminates appropriations for: (1) benefit payments for employee tuition assistance and employee child care, and (2) Energy Demonstration Projects. Decreases appropriations for: (1) business continuity and disaster recovery, and (2) the Wounded Warrior Program. (Sec. 1908) Decreases appropriations for salaries and/or expenses of: (1) the Joint Economic and Taxation Committees, (2) the Office of Compliance, and (3) the Congressional Budget Office (CBO). Increases appropriations for the Capitol Police. (Sec. 1913) Requires the level and period of availability for the remainder of FY2011 for each item under "Architect of the Capitol" (AOC) in the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2010 to be determined in accordance with an allocation plan submitted by the AOC and approved by the congressional appropriations committees. Specifies a limit for the aggregate level for all such items. Excludes the Senate Office Buildings from such requirement. (Sec. 1914) Decreases appropriations for: (1) the Library of Congress for salaries and expenses, the Copyright Office, Congressional Research Service (CRS), and Books for the Blind and Physically Handicapped; (2) the Government Printing Office (GPO) Revolving Fund; (3) GPO for the Office of Superintendent of Documents; (4) the Government Accountability Office (GAO); (5) the Open World Leadership Center Trust Fund; and (6) the Library of Congress digital collections and educational curricula program. Eliminates appropriations for the operation of Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Commission and the Durham Museum in Omaha, Nebraska. (Sec. 1920) Amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1999 with respect to the GPO-established program under which voluntary separation incentive payments are offered to certain eligible GPO employees for voluntary separation through resignation or retirement. Repeals the requirement that the Public Printer remit to OPM for deposit in the Treasury to the credit of the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund 15% of the final basic pay of each employee covered under the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) or the Federal Employee Retirement System (FERS) to whom such voluntary separation incentive has been paid. (Sec. 1921) Increases the amount of: (1) payments received from the leasing of space in the GAO Building which shall be available for FY2010 use, and (2) reimbursements received as a result of audits of government corporations which shall be available for FY2010 use. Reduces, however, the amount available for FY2010 use of reimbursements received as a result of audits of federal agencies. (Sec. 1923) Eliminates appropriations for the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development. Title X: Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies - (Sec. 2001) Increases appropriations for military construction for the Army. Decreases appropriations for military construction for the Navy and Marine Corps, the Air Force, and defense-wide. (Sec. 2002) Increases appropriations for military construction the Army National Guard. Decreases funds for military construction for the Air National Guard, the Army Reserve, the Navy Reserve, and the Air Force Reserve. (Sec. 2003) Increases appropriations for family housing construction for the Navy and Marine Corps and the Air Force. Decreases appropriations for family housing construction for the Army and for the Family Housing Improvement Fund. Eliminates appropriations for family housing construction, defense-wide. (Sec. 2004) Increases appropriations for the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program. Decreases appropriations for chemical demilitarization construction, defense-wide, the Homeowners Assistance Fund, and the Department of Defense Base Closure Accounts of 1990 and 2005. (Sec. 2005) Increases appropriations for family housing operation and maintenance for the Air Force and defense-wide. Decreases appropriations for family housing operation and maintenance for the Army and the Navy and Marine Corps. (Sec. 2006) Makes certain funding restrictions, requirements, and/or set-asides under the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2010 inapplicable to funds made available in this Division. (Sec. 2007) Increases appropriations for Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), departmental administration, general operating expenses. (Sec. 2008) Decreases appropriations for VA information technology systems. (Sec. 2009) Decreases appropriations for VA for construction, major projects. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit to the appropriations committees an FY2011 spending plan at a level of detail below the account level. (Sec. 2010) Decreases appropriations for VA for construction, minor projects. (Sec. 2011) Decreases appropriations for: (1) the VA for construction of state extended care facilities; and (2) the Armed Forces Retirement Home. (Sec. 2013) Makes the provisions included in title IV (Overseas Contingency Operations) of division E (Military Construction and Veterans Affairs and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2010) of Public Law 111-117 (Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2010) inapplicable to the provisos of funds appropriated by this division under Military Construction, Army and under Military Construction, Air Force. (Sec. 2014) Rescinds specified funds within various military construction accounts under prior military construction appropriations acts. (Sec. 2019) Rescinds specified funds for the Department of Defense Base Closure Account 2005 under prior appropriations. (Sec. 2020) Appropriates funds for Army military construction, Air Force military construction, and defense-wide military construction for overseas contingency operations. (Sec. 2021) Appropriates funds for FY2012 for VA medical services, medical support and compliance, and medical facilities. (Sec. 2022) Allows specified funds appropriated to the VA for FY2011 to be transferred to the Joint Department of Defense-Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Demonstration Fund for use for combined medical facilities. (Sec. 2023) Allows for the transfer of funds from the VA's Medical Care Collections Fund to the above Fund. (Sec. 2024) Rescinds specified funds for VA information technology systems under the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2010.
Title XI: State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs - (Sec. 2102) Increases appropriations for Administration of Foreign Affairs, Diplomatic and Consular Programs. Decreases appropriations for Administration of Foreign Affairs for: (1) the Department of State and the Foreign Service, and for worldwide security protection; (2) the Office of the Inspector General; (3) emergencies in the diplomatic and consular service; (4) representation allowances; (5) the American Institute in Taiwan; (6) civilian stabilization initiative; (7) capital investment fund; and (8) protection of foreign missions and officials. (Sec. 2103) Decreases appropriations for: (1) International Organizations, contributions to international organizations; (2) International Organizations, contributions for international peacekeeping activities; and (3) International Commissions, International Fisheries Commissions. Eliminates appropriations for: (1) the United States Institute of Peace, and (2) the East-West Center. (Sec. 2104) Increases appropriations for the International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico, salaries and expenses. Decreases appropriations for such Commission for construction. Decreases appropriations for: (1) International Commissions, American sections; (2) the Asia Foundation; (3) the Commission for the Preservation of America's Heritage Abroad, salaries and expenses; (4) the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom, salaries and expenses; (4) the Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe, salaries and expenses; (5) the Congressional-Executive Commission on the People's Republic of China, salaries and expenses; and (6) the United States-China Economic and Security Review Commission. (Sec. 2105) Decreases appropriations for the Broadcasting Board of Governors: (1) international broadcasting operations, and (2) capital improvements. (Sec. 2106) Decreases appropriations for: (1) Administration of Foreign Affairs, educational and cultural exchange programs; and (2) the National Endowment for Democracy. Decreases appropriations for Bilateral Economic Assistance for: (1) the Inter-American Foundation, and (2) the African Development Foundation. (Sec. 2107) Decreases appropriations for the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), Funds Appropriated to the President for: (1) operating expenses, (2) civilian stabilization initiative, (3) capital investment fund, and (4) the Office of Inspector General. (Sec. 2108) Decreases appropriations for Bilateral Economic Assistance for: (1) Funds Appropriated to the President, development assistance; (2) Funds Appropriated to the President, assistance for Europe, Eurasia and Central Asia; and (3) Independent Agencies, the Millennium Challenge Corporation. (Sec. 2109) Decreases appropriations for Bilateral Economic Assistance, Funds Appropriated to the President for: (1) the Economic Support Fund, and (2) the Democracy Fund. Decreases appropriations for the Department of the Treasury: (1) international affairs technical assistance, and (2) debt restructuring.
(Sec. 2110) Decreases appropriations for Bilateral Economic Assistance for Funds Appropriated to the President for: (1) international disaster assistance, and (2) transition initiatives. (Sec. 2111) Decreases appropriations for Bilateral Economic Assistance, Department of State for: (1) migration and refugee assistance, and (2) the United States Emergency Refugee and Migration Assistance Fund. (Sec. 2112) Decreases appropriations for Bilateral Economic Assistance, the Peace Corps. (Sec. 2113) Decreases appropriations for International Security Assistance, Department of State: (1) nonproliferation, anti-terrorism, demining and related programs, and (2) peacekeeping operations. (Sec. 2114) Appropriates funds for International Security Assistance, Funds Appropriated to the President, Pakistan Counterinsurgency Capability Fund. Increases: (1) appropriations for International Security Assistance, Funds Appropriated to the President, foreign military financing program; and (2) amounts available from such funds for Israel and Egypt. Makes appropriations from such funds available for Jordan. (Sec. 2115) Decreases appropriations for Multilateral Assistance, Funds Appropriated to the President: (1) international organizations and programs, (2) the Global Environment Facility, (3) the International Development Association, (4) the Enterprise for the Americas Multilateral Investment Fund, (5) the African Development Fund, and (6) the International Fund for Agricultural Development. (Sec. 2116) Decreases the amount available for the Overseas Private Investment Corporation: (1) noncredit account, and (2) program account. Decreases appropriations for Funds Appropriated to the President, trade and development agency. (Sec. 2117) Decreases appropriations for Administration of Foreign Affairs: (1) embassy security, construction, and maintenance; and (2) worldwide security upgrades, acquisition, and construction. Decreases appropriations for Administration of Foreign Affairs, repatriation loans program account: (1) the direct loan program, and (2) related administrative costs. Decreases appropriations for Bilateral Economic Assistance, Funds Appropriated to the President, Development Credit Authority. (Sec. 2118) Decreases appropriations for Bilateral Economic Assistance, Funds Appropriated to the President, global health and child security for: (1) the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), and (2) the Department of State. Decreases a set-aside for a U.S. contribution to the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria. (Sec. 2119) Eliminates appropriations for: (1) Administration of Foreign Affairs, the Buying Power Maintenance Account; (2) Bilateral Economic Assistance, Funds Appropriated to the President, the Complex Crises Fund; (3) Bilateral Economic Assistance, Funds Appropriated to the President, the International Fund for Ireland; (4) Multilateral Assistance, Funds Appropriated to the President, the Clean Technology Fund; (5) Multilateral Assistance, Funds Appropriated to the President, the Strategic Climate Fund; and (6) Multilateral Assistance, Funds Appropriated to the President, the Asian Development Fund. (Sec. 2120) Rescinds specified amounts from unobligated balances for: (1) the Export-Import Bank of the United States, subsidiary appropriations; (2) the Buying Power Maintenance Account; (3) the Development Assistance Account, as identified by Treasury Appropriation Fund Symbols 7206/111021; (4) the Assistance for the Independent States of the Former Soviet Union Account, as identified by Treasury Appropriation Fund Symbols 7206/111093, 7207/121093, and 72X1093; and (5) the International Narcotics Control and Law Enforcement Account, as identified by Treasury Appropriation Fund Symbols, 11X1022, 1106/121022, and 191105/111022. (Sec. 2121) Sets forth specified reporting requirements. (Sec. 2122) Makes specific amounts for diplomatic and consular programs under PL 111-117 inapplicable to appropriations under this division. Prohibits funds appropriated by this division from being used to support the United States Ambassador's Fund for Cultural Preservation. States that certain funds under PL 111-117 "should" rather than "shall" be applied to appropriations under this title for: (1) development assistance, and (2) the Economic Support Fund. Makes certain provisions of PL 111-117 inapplicable to specified provisions of this division. Decreases appropriations available for family planning and reproductive health. Prohibits funds appropriated by this division for the Department of State, foreign operations, and related programs from being made available to: (1) the United Nations Population Fund; and (2) any foreign nongovernmental organization that promotes or performs abortion, except in cases of rape or incest or when the life of the mother would be endangered if the fetus were carried to term. Increases appropriations for the West Bank and Gaza. (Sec. 2123) Revises the conditions of certain economic support fund assistance to: (1) Egypt, and (2) Afghanistan and Pakistan. Increases appropriations available for international peacekeeping activities in Somalia. Prohibits funds from being made available to: (1) the Armed Forces of Lebanon until the Secretary of State reports to Congress that such funding is in the U.S. National security interest, and (2) the Export-Import Bank of the United States for new financing to any person subject to certain sanctions under the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996. States that certain funds under PL 111-117 "should" rather that "shall" be applied to appropriations under this division for: (1) development grants, and (2) reconciliation programs, (3) democracy and education programs in Timor-Leste, and (4) USAID programs for people with disabilities in developing countries. Reduces appropriations that may be made available to Burma for democracy and humanitarian programs. (Sec. 2124) Prohibits making any funds available under this division for assistance to Afghanistan until the Secretary of State, in consultation with USAID, makes certain certifications to Congress concerning anti-corruption activities, public participation in governance, women's rights, and assistance monitoring. Specifies authorized, restricted, and prohibited uses of funds appropriated under this division for assistance to Afghanistan, including relating to women and reintegration into Afghan society of former combatants. Prohibits funds available under this division from being used to enter into a permanent basing rights agreement between the United States and Afghanistan. Requires a detailed spending plan for assistance to Afghanistan with clear goals and benchmarks, as well as a coordinated audit and inspection plan of U.S. assistance for, and civilian operations in, Afghanistan. Title XII: Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies - (Sec. 2201) Increases appropriations for FY2011 for the Department of Transportation (DOT) for Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) operations, allocating a specified amount for aviation regulation and certification activities. (Sec. 2202) Decreases appropriations for FAA facilities and equipment. (Sec. 2203) Eliminates appropriations for: (1) the Office of the Secretary of Transportation for national infrastructure investments, (2) the Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) for surface transportation priorities, (3) the Federal Transit Administration (FTA) for grants for energy efficiency and greenhouse gas reductions, (4) the Federal Railroad Administration (FRA) railroad safety technology program and for capital assistance for high speed rail corridors and intercity passenger rail service, (5) the Maritime Administration (MARAD) for assistance to small shipyards, and (6) the FTA for grants to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA). (Sec. 2204) Decreases appropriations for: (1) FAA research, engineering, and development; (2) FTA capital investment grants; (3) the FRA rail line relocation and improvement program; and (4) FRA capital and debt service grants to the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (AMTRAK). (Sec. 2208) Increases appropriations for MARAD operations and training, with the increase allocated to the reimbursement of overcharged midshipmen fees at the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy for academic years 2003-2004 through 2008-2009. Makes such reimbursement the final and conclusive disposition of claims for such overcharges. (Sec. 2209) Rescinds prior year and certain other unobligated balances for: (1) FRA capital assistance for high speed rail corridors and intercity passenger rail service, (2) the Office of the Secretary for national infrastructure investments, (3) the FTA for capital investment grants, (4) the FRA railroad safety technology program, (5) FRA capital assistance to states for intercity passenger rail service, and (6) FTA energy efficiency and greenhouse gas reduction grants. (Sec. 2215) Eliminates appropriations for: (1) federal-aid highway restoration, repair, construction, and other activities; and (2) the Secretary to continue an independent and comprehensive study and analysis of the Missouri River Projects located within the Missouri River basin as well as for a multiagency task force to formulate DOT coordination with the Departments of Energy (DOE), of Commerce, and of Agriculture (USDA) to ensure a comprehensive understanding of the full value of river flow support to users in the Mississippi and Missouri Rivers. (Sec. 2216) Declares that certain prohibitions on the use of funds to enforce charter bus regulations shall not apply to funds appropriated for such purpose under this Act. (Sec. 2217) Eliminates appropriations within the accounts of the FHWA, the FRA, and the FTA for: (1) ferry boats and ferry terminal facilities, (2) federal lands, (3) discretionary interstate maintenance, (4) transportation, (5) the community and system preservation program, (6) the Delta Region Transportation Development Program, (7) the rail line relocation and improvement program, (8) rail-highway crossing hazard eliminations, (9) capital investment grants, (10) alternatives analysis, and (11) bus and bus facilities. (Sec. 2219) Prohibits the distribution to states of a certain obligation limitation for specified federal-aid highway programs for FY2011, including: (1) the interstate maintenance discretionary program; (2) the Transportation, Community, and Systems Preservation Program; (3) the Ferry Boats discretionary program; and (4) the Delta Region Transportation Development program. Redistributes such obligation limitation for the following programs as follows: (1) 20% to the interstate maintenance program, (2) 26% to the surface transportation program, (3) 17% to the highway bridge program, (4) 5% to the highway safety improvement program, (5) 7% to the congestion mitigation and air quality maintenance program, and (6) 25% for the national highway system program. (Sec. 2220) Decreases appropriations for the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) for: (1) tenant-based housing rental assistance (with no funds available for incremental rental voucher assistance for use through a supported housing program administered in conjunction with the Department of Veterans Affairs [VA]), (2) the Public Housing Operating Fund, (3) the Public Housing Capital Fund, (4) Native American housing block grants, (5) the Community Development Fund (with such funds available only for the Community Development Block Grant [CDBG] Program, but no funds available for the Sustainable Communities Initiative), (6) the HOME Investment Partnerships Program, and (7) the Lead Hazard Reduction Program of the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes, (Sec. 2221) Increases appropriations for: (1) project-based housing rental assistance; (2) Federal Housing Administration (FHA), the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund, administrative contract expenses; and (3) AMTRAK Office of Inspector General for salaries and expenses. (Sec. 2222) Eliminates appropriations for the following housing and related programs: (1) revitalization of severely distressed public housing (HOPE VI), (2) Native Hawaiian housing block grants, (3) housing counseling assistance, (4) the Energy Innovation Fund, and (5) Brownfields redevelopment. (Sec. 2230) Rescinds unobligated balances for: (1) Brownfields redevelopment, (2) HOPE VI, (3) a Sustainable Communities Initiative under the Community Development Fund, and (4) the Housing Programs, Energy Innovation Fund. (Sec. 2234) Makes appropriations for FY2011 for necessary expenses of information technology modernization, including development and deployment of a Next Generation of Voucher Management System and modernized FHA systems. Makes available for obligation no more than 25% of such funds for information technology modernization until the HUD Secretary submits to Congress a plan for the expenditure of funds for each FHA modernization project. Eliminates certain funds for combating mortgage fraud, among other specified items. (Sec. 2236) Declares that no rescission made by this title shall apply to any amount previously designated by Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget or the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act). (Sec. 2237) Decreases appropriations for housing for the elderly. Prohibits the use of such funds for capital advances or project housing rental assistance contracts. (Sec. 2238) Decreases appropriations for housing for persons with disabilities. Prohibits the use of such funds for: (1) capital advances or project housing rental assistance contracts, or (2) amendments or renewals of tenant-based assistance contracts entered into before FY2005. Division C: Stimulus Rescissions - (Sec. 3001) Rescinds all unobligated balances remaining available as of February 11, 2011, of the discretionary appropriations provided by division A of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (ARRA) with respect to: (1) the Departments of Agriculture (USDA), of Commerce, of Justice, of Defense (DOD), of Energy (DOE), of the Treasury, of Homeland Security (DHS), of the Interior, of Labor, of Health and Human Services (HHS), of Education, of Veterans Affairs (VA), of State, of Transportation (DOT), and of Housing and Urban Development (HUD); (2) all related agencies, including the Food and Drug Administration, the Army Corps of Engineers, the Small Business Administration (SBA), and the Government Accountability Office; and (3) every department or agency under the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health Act or the HITECH Act. Exempts from such rescission any funds appropriated or otherwise made available to Offices of Inspector General and to the Recovery Act Accountability and Transparency Board. (Sec. 3002) Prohibits federal agencies administering ARRA funds from providing funding or reimbursement to any entity awarded such funds for the cost associated with physical signage or other advertisement indicating that a project is funded by ARRA. Division D: Miscellaneous Provisions - (Sec. 4001) Sets up Spending Reduction Accounts for specified federal departments and agencies consisting of the amount by which each applicable allocation of new budget authority made by the Committee on Appropriations of the House exceeds the corresponding amount of proposed new budget authority. (Sec. 4002) Prohibits the use of certain funds made available by this Act for the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to provide grants under the Urban Area Security Initiative to more than 25 high-risk urban areas. (Sec. 4003) Makes specified appropriations to the Department of Justice, Office of Justice Programs, to create and implement a National Strategy for Child Exploitation Prevention and Interdiction under the PROTECT Our Children Act of 2008. (Sec. 4004) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to carry out the purposes of the Presidential Election Campaign Fund or the Presidential Primary Matching Payment Account under the Internal Revenue Code. (Sec. 4005) Prohibits the use of funds made available in this Act to enforce the requirements of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 for firefighter hiring grants to career, volunteer, and combination fire departments under the pre-September 11, 2001, fire grant program. (Sec. 4006) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to implement a specified Report and Order of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) relating to the matter of preserving the open Internet and broadband industry practices. (Sec. 4007) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act for the payment of fees and other expenses awarded to a prevailing party (other than the United States) in an adversarial federal administrative or judicial action. (Sec. 4008) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to implement, administer, or enforce National Emission Standards for Hazardous Air Pollutants From the Portland Cement Manufacturing Industry and Standards of Performance for Portland Cement Plants published by the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) on September 9, 2010. (Sec. 4009) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to pay the salaries and expenses of: (1) the Director of the White House Office of Health Reform; (2) the Assistant to the President for Energy and Climate Change; (3) the Special Envoy for Climate Change; (4) the Special Advisor for Green Jobs, Enterprise and Innovation, Council on Environmental Quality; (5) the Senior Advisor to the Secretary of the Treasury assigned to the Presidential Task Force on the Auto Industry and Senior Counselor for Manufacturing Policy; (6) the White House Director of Urban Affairs; (7) the Special Envoy to oversee the closure of the Detention Center at Guantanamo Bay; (8) the Special Master for TARP Executive Compensation, Department of the Treasury; or (9) the FCC Associate General Counsel and Chief Diversity Officer. (Sec. 4010) Reduces by specified amounts certain funds otherwise provided by this Act for the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CMS), and the National Institutes of Health of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). (Sec. 4011) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to provide any of the following types of assistance to Chad: (1) international military education and training (IMET), (2) foreign military financing (FMF), (3) excess defense articles, (4) foreign military forces capacity assistance, and (5) direct commercial sales of military equipment. (Sec. 4012) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to: (1) implement, administer, or enforce certain Department of Education final regulations on "Program Integrity: Gainful Employment--New Programs" (to establish a process under which an institution applies for approval to offer an educational program that leads to gainful employment in a recognized occupation) or enforce a related section of the Code of Federal Regulations (reporting and disclosure requirements for programs that prepare students for gainful employment in a recognized occupation); (2) issue another Department of Education final rule or otherwise implement a specified different proposed rule on "Program Integrity: Gainful Employment" (to establish measures for determining whether certain postsecondary educational programs lead to gainful employment in recognized occupations, and the conditions under which they remain eligible for student financial assistance programs); or (3) promulgate or enforce any new regulation or rule with respect to the definition or application of the term "gainful employment" under the Higher Education Act of 1965. (Sec. 4013) Prohibits the availability of funds under this Act to Planned Parenthood Federation of America, Inc. or any of its specified state affiliates. (Sec. 4014) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act by the EPA Environmental Appeals Board to consider, review, reject, remand, or otherwise invalidate any permit issued under the Clean Air Act for Outer Continental Shelf sources located offshore of the states (e.g. Alaska) along the Arctic Coast. (Sec. 4015) Prohibits EPA use of funds made available by this Act to implement, administer, or enforce any statutory or regulatory requirement pertaining to emissions of carbon dioxide, methane, nitrous oxide, sulfur hexafluoride, hydrofluorocarbons, or perfluorocarbons from stationary sources (pollutant-emitting buildings, structures, facilities, or installations) that is issued or becomes applicable or effective after January 1, 2011. (Sec. 4016) Prohibits the payment of funds made available by this Act to any employee, officer, contractor, or grantee of any department or agency funded by Division B title VIII (Labor, Health and Human Services, Education, and Related Agencies) of this Act to implement: (1) the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, or (2) "Title I: Coverage, Medicare, Medicaid, and Revenues" or "Title II: Subtitle B: Health" of the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010. (Sec. 4017) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to carry out the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010, or any amendment made by either it or the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act. (Sec. 4018) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to pay the salary of any officer or employee of any federal department or agency with respect to carrying out the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010, or any amendment made by either such Public Law. (Sec. 4019) Prohibits use by the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) of funds made available by this Act to implement or enforce the requirements of the Internal Revenue Code under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act that: (1) individuals maintain minimum essential health insurance coverage for themselves and their dependents, and (2) providers of such coverage file with IRS specified related informational returns. (Sec. 4020) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to take any action to effect or implement the disestablishment, closure, or realignment of the U.S. Joint Forces Command. (Sec. 4021) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to change any Foreign Service rate of salary or basic pay pursuant to the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2009. (Sec. 4022) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act for the Community Connect broadband grant program administered by the Rural Utilities Service of the Department of Agriculture (USDA). (Sec. 4023) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to provide assistance to Saudi Arabia. (Sec. 4024) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act for International Military Education and Training (IMET) or for Nonproliferation, Anti-terrorism, Demining and Related Programs for assistance for Saudi Arabia. (Sec. 4026) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to pay the salaries and expenses of USDA personnel to provide nonrecourse marketing assistance loans for mohair under the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008. (Sec. 4027) Prohibits HHS from using funds made available by division B of this Act to implement or enforce the requirement of the Public Health Service Act, as added by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, that a health plan: (1) report to the Secretary of HHS about the ratio of an incurred loss (or incurred claims) plus the loss adjustment expense (or change in contract reserves) to earned premiums; and (2) give an annual rebate to each enrollee in certain circumstances. (Sec. 4028) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to implement the Klamath Dam Removal and Sedimentation Study. (Sec. 4029) Prohibits the Secretary of Agriculture from using funds made available by this Act to implement or enforce the Travel Management Rule, Subpart B (relating to the designation of roads, trails, and areas for motor vehicle use), in any administrative unit of the National Forest System. (Sec. 4030) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to require a person licensed to import, manufacture, or deal in firearms or ammunition to report information to the Department of Justice regarding the sale of multiple rifles or shotguns to the same person. (Sec. 4031) Prohibits the use of certain DOD funds made available by this Act for official representation purposes. (Sec. 4032) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to develop, carry out, implement, or otherwise enforce proposed regulations of the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement of the Department of the Interior with respect to improving protection of streams from the adverse impacts of surface coal mining operations. (Sec. 4033) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to develop, promulgate, evaluate, implement, provide oversight to, or backstop total maximum daily loads or watershed implementation plans for the Chesapeake Bay Watershed. (Sec. 4034) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to pay the salary of any HHS officer or employee who develops or promulgates regulations or guidance with regard to American Health Benefit Exchanges under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act. (Sec. 4035) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to implement, administer, or enforce the EPA Water Quality Standards for the state of Florida's Lakes and Flowing Waters. (Sec. 4036) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act for the design, renovation, construction, or rental of any United Nations headquarters in any location in the United States. (Sec. 4037) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act for the construction of an ethanol blender pump or an ethanol storage facility. (Sec. 4038) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to implement, establish, or create a National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) Climate Service (NCS), as described in a specified notice in the Federal Register. (Sec. 4039) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to EPA, the Army Corps of Engineers, or the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement to carry out, implement, administer, or enforce any policy or procedure set forth in: (1) a specified EPA-Department of the Army memorandum on Enhanced Surface Coal Mining Pending Permit Coordination Procedures; or (2) the EPA guidance entitled "Improving EPA Review of Appalachian Surface Coal Mining Operations under the Clean Water Act, National Environmental Policy Act, and the Environmental Justice Executive Order." (Sec. 4040) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to develop or approve for any fishery under the jurisdiction of the South Atlantic, Mid-Atlantic, New England, or Gulf of Mexico Fishery Management Council a new Limited Access Privilege Program (LAPP) under which federal permits are issued to harvest a quantity of fish representing a portion of the total allowable catch (TAC). (Sec. 4041) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act for a specified study of the Missouri River Projects authorized in the Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2009. (Sec. 4042) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act for contributions to the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC). (Sec. 4043) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to implement two specified decisions of the EPA Administrator, both entitled "Partial Grant and Partial Denial of Clean Air Act Waiver Application Submitted by Growth Energy To Increase the Allowable Ethanol Content of Gasoline to 15 Percent." (Sec. 4044) Prohibits the EPA Administrator from using funds made available by this Act to carry out authority under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to prohibit the specification of any defined area as a disposal site for the discharge of dredged or fill material into navigable waters. (Sec. 4045) Prohibits EPA use of funds made available by this Act to develop, propose, finalize, implement, administer, or enforce any regulation that identifies or lists fossil fuel combustion waste as hazardous waste or otherwise makes it subject to regulation under the Solid Waste Disposal Act. (Sec. 4046) Prohibits the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) from using funds made available by this Act to establish and maintain the publicly available consumer product safety information database. (Sec. 4047) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to pay the salary of any officer or employee of the HHS Center for Consumer Information and Insurance Oversight. (Sec. 4048) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to modify the national primary ambient air quality standard or the national secondary ambient air quality standard applicable to coarse particulate matter under the Clean Air Act. (Sec. 4049) None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to pay the salary of any officer or employee of HHS, the Department of Labor, or the Department of the Treasury who takes any action to specify or define, through regulations, guidelines, or otherwise, the essential health benefits package under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act. (Sec. 4050) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to establish the Independent Payment Advisory Board (also known as the Independent Medicare Advisory Board) under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act. (Sec. 4051) Prohibits the use of funds made available by this Act to carry out a specified prohibition against allocation of Education Jobs Fund appropriations to Texas (including local education agencies in Texas) unless the Governor of Texas assures the Secretary of Education that the state will maintain state support for elementary and secondary education for FY2011-FY2013 at a percentage of total revenues available to the state equal to or greater than the corresponding percentage for FY2011 before enactment of Public Law 111-226.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c112:H.R.1:"/></bill>
