<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="112" type="h" number="1016" abbrev="H.R. 1016"><status date="2011-05-10T17:32:00-04:00">vote</status><introduced date="2011-03-10"/><title>Assessing Progress in Haiti Act</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="112" type="s" number="1576"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>International affairs</subject><subject>Caribbean area</subject><subject>Congressional oversight</subject><subject>Disaster relief and insurance</subject><subject>Foreign aid and international relief</subject><subject>Haiti</subject><subject>Immigration status and procedures</subject><subject>Infectious and parasitic diseases</subject><subject>International organizations and cooperation</subject><subject>Latin America</subject><subject>Multilateral development programs</subject><subject>Natural disasters</subject><subject>Reconstruction and stabilization</subject><subject>Refugees, asylum, displaced persons</subject><subject>United Nations</subject><subject>World health</subject></subjects><summary>4/26/2012--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on May 10, 2011. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Assessing Progress in Haiti Act - Directs the President to report to Congress on the status of post-earthquake humanitarian, reconstruction, and development efforts in Haiti, including efforts to prevent the spread of cholera and treat persons infected with the disease. Requires such report to evaluate: (1) the overall progress of relief, recovery, and reconstruction in Haiti, including U.S. government programs, programs to protect vulnerable populations, and projects to improve water, sanitation, and health; (2) the extent to which U.S. and international efforts are in line with the government of Haiti's priorities and are working through Haitian ministries and local authorities; (3) coordination among U.S. government agencies and coordination between the U.S. government and U.N. agencies, international financial institutions, and other bilateral donors; (4) mechanisms for communicating the progress of recovery and reconstruction to Haitian citizens; (5) mechanisms through which Haitian civil society and the Haitian diaspora are participating in recovery and reconstruction; and (6) Haiti's suitability to receive aliens who are removed, excluded, or deported from the United States and steps Haiti is taking to strengthen its capacity in this regard.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c112:H.R.1016:"/></bill>
