<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="112" type="h" number="1084" abbrev="H.R. 1084"><status date="2011-03-15">introduced</status><introduced date="2011-03-15"/><title>Fracturing Responsibility and Awareness of Chemicals Act of 2011</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="112" type="s" number="587"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>Environmental protection</subject><subject>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</subject><subject>Alternative and renewable resources</subject><subject>Business records</subject><subject>Emergency medical services and trauma care</subject><subject>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)</subject><subject>Environmental regulatory procedures</subject><subject>Government information and archives</subject><subject>Hazardous wastes and toxic substances</subject><subject>Oil and gas</subject><subject>Water quality</subject><subject>Water use and supply</subject></subjects><summary>3/15/2011--Introduced.
Fracturing Responsibility and Awareness of Chemicals Act of 2011 - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to repeal the exemption from restrictions on underground injection of fluids or propping agents granted to hydraulic fracturing operations related to oil, gas, or geothermal production activities under such Act. Requires: (1) state underground injection programs to direct a person conducting hydraulic fracturing operations to disclose to the state (or the Administrator if the Administrator has primary enforcement responsibility in such state) the chemicals intended for use in underground injections prior to the commencement of such operations and the chemicals actually used after the end of such operations; and (2) a state or the Administrator to make such disclosure available to the public. Requires a person conducting hydraulic fracturing operations, when a medical emergency exists and the proprietary chemical formula of a chemical used in such operations is necessary for medical treatment, to disclose such formula or the specific chemical identity of a trade secret chemical to the state, the Administrator, or the treating physician or nurse upon request, regardless of whether a written statement of need or a confidentiality agreement has been provided. Authorizes such person to require a written statement of need and a confidentiality agreement as soon thereafter as circumstances permit.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c112:H.R.1084:"/></bill>
