<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="112" type="h" number="1112" abbrev="H.R. 1112"><status date="2011-03-16">introduced</status><introduced date="2011-03-16"/><title>National Association of Registered Agents and Brokers Reform Act of 2011</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="112" type="s" number="2342"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>Finance and financial sector</subject><subject>Consumer affairs</subject><subject>Criminal justice information and records</subject><subject>Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises</subject><subject>Insurance industry and regulation</subject><subject>State and local government operations</subject></subjects><summary>3/16/2011--Introduced.
National Association of Registered Agents and Brokers Reform Act of 2011 - Amends the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act to repeal the contingent conditions under which the National Association of Registered Agents and Brokers (NARAB) shall not be established. Reestablishes the NARAB without contingent conditions as a nonprofit corporation to prescribe, on a multi-state basis, licensing and insurance producer qualification requirements and conditions. Retains states' regulatory authority over: (1) licensing, supervision, disciplining, and setting of licensing fees for insurance producers; and (2) insurance-related consumer protection and unfair trade practices. Prohibits NARAB from establishing criteria that unfairly limit the ability of a small insurance producer to become a member of NARAB. Authorizes NARAB to: (1) establish membership criteria, including a mandatory criminal background check for state-licensed insurance producers, and (2) deny membership to a state-licensed insurance producer on the basis of the criminal history information obtained. Authorizes the NARAB to deny membership to any state-licensed insurance producer for failure to meet membership criteria. States that NARAB membership authorizes an insurance producer to engage in the business of insurance in any state for any lines of insurance specified in the producer's home state license, including claims adjustments and settlement, risk management, and specified insurance-related consulting activities. Retains state regulatory jurisdiction regarding consumer protection and market conduct. Requires NARAB to: (1) receive and investigate consumer complaints, maintaining a toll-free telephone number; and (2) refer any such complaint to the state insurance regulator. Authorizes the NARAB to coordinate with state insurance regulators to establish: (1) a central clearinghouse, and (2) a national database for the collection of regulatory information concerning the activities of insurance producers.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c112:H.R.1112:"/></bill>
