<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="112" type="h" number="112" abbrev="H.R. 112"><status date="2011-01-05">introduced</status><introduced date="2011-01-05"/><title>Kristen's Act Reauthorization of 2011</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="112" type="h" number="3082"/><relatedbill session="112" type="s" number="1263"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>Crime and law enforcement</subject><subject>Advisory bodies</subject><subject>Aging</subject><subject>Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation</subject><subject>Criminal justice information and records</subject><subject>Department of Justice</subject><subject>Emergency communications systems</subject><subject>Executive agency funding and structure</subject><subject>Government information and archives</subject><subject>Intergovernmental relations</subject><subject>Law enforcement administration and funding</subject><subject>Public-private cooperation</subject><subject>Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations</subject><subject>State and local government operations</subject></subjects><summary>1/5/2011--Introduced.
National Silver Alert Act of 2011 - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) establish a national Silver Alert communications network within the Department of Justice (DOJ) to assist regional and local search efforts for missing seniors; (2) assign a DOJ officer to serve as the Silver Alert Coordinator to coordinate the network with states; and (3) award grants to states for support of Silver Alert plans and the network. Defines "missing senior" as any individual who is reported as missing to or by a law enforcement agency and who meets state requirements for designation as a missing senior. Directs the Coordinator to: (1) establish minimum standards for the issuance and dissemination of alerts issued through the network; and (2) make available to states, local governments, law enforcement agencies, and other concerned entities network training and information. Kristen's Act Reauthorization of 2011 - Directs the Attorney General to make competitive grants to public agencies and/or nonprofit private organizations to: (1) maintain a national resource center and database for tracking missing adults; and (2) provide assistance and to law enforcement agencies, families, and victim advocates in locating and recovering missing adults.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c112:H.R.112:"/></bill>
