<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="111" type="h" number="1016" abbrev="H.R. 1016"><status date="2009-10-22">enacted</status><introduced date="2009-02-12"/><title>Veterans Health Care Budget Reform and Transparency Act of 2009</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="111" type="hr" number="804"/><relatedbill session="111" type="s" number="423"/><relatedbill session="111" type="s" number="423"/><relatedbill session="111" type="s" number="423"/><relatedbill session="111" type="s" number="423"/><relatedbill session="111" type="s" number="423"/><relatedbill session="111" type="s" number="423"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>Armed forces and national security</subject><subject>Appropriations</subject><subject>Budget process</subject><subject>Congressional oversight</subject><subject>Department of Veterans Affairs</subject><subject>Executive agency funding and structure</subject><subject>Health facilities and institutions</subject><subject>Health programs administration and funding</subject><subject>Veterans' medical care</subject></subjects><summary>10/22/2009--Public Law. (This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on October 8, 2009. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Veterans Health Care Budget Reform and Transparency Act of 2009 - Directs the President to include in annual budget justification documents submitted to Congress information on estimates of appropriations for the fiscal year following the fiscal year for which the budget is submitted for the following accounts of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA): (1) Medical Services; (2) Medical Support and Compliance; and (3) Medical Facilities. Requires annually for such accounts, beginning with FY2011, discretionary new budget authority to: (1) be made available for that fiscal year; and (2) include, for each such account, advance discretionary new budget authority that first becomes available for the first fiscal year after the budget year.
Directs the VA Secretary to report annually to Congress on the sufficiency of VA resources for the proceeding fiscal year with respect to the provision of medical care, including estimates of the workload and demand data for that fiscal year. Requires the Comptroller General to: (1) annually study the adequacy and accuracy of VA baseline model projections for health care expenditures for that fiscal year; and (2) report study results, during 2011 through 2013, to the congressional veterans, appropriations, and budget committees.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c111:H.R.1016:"/></bill>
