<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="111" type="h" number="1044" abbrev="H.R. 1044"><status date="2009-07-15T12:35:00-04:00">vote</status><introduced date="2009-02-12"/><title>Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial Enhancement Act of 2009</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="111" type="s" number="1469"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>Public lands and natural resources</subject><subject>Accidents</subject><subject>California</subject><subject>Government buildings, facilities, and property</subject><subject>Hazardous wastes and toxic substances</subject><subject>Land transfers</subject><subject>Military facilities and property</subject><subject>Monuments and memorials</subject><subject>Parks, recreation areas, trails</subject><subject>Travel and tourism</subject></subjects><summary>7/15/2009--Passed House amended. Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial Enhancement Act of 2009 - Amends the Port Chicago National Memorial Act of 1992 to require the Secretary of the Interior to administer the Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial as a unit of the National Park System. Directs the Secretary of Defense to transfer a specified parcel of land within the proposed boundary on the map entitled "Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial, Proposed Boundary," dated August 2005, to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior if: (1) the land is excess to military needs; and (2) all environmental remediation actions necessary to respond to environmental contamination have been completed. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement with the Secretary of Defense to provide as much public access as possible to the Memorial without interfering with military needs. Makes such authority no longer applicable if the Memorial ceases to be an enclave within the Concord Naval Weapons Station. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement with the city of Concord, California, and the East Bay Regional Park District to establish and operate a facility for visitor orientation and parking, administrative offices, and curatorial storage for the Memorial. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Defense should remediate remaining environmental contamination related to the land. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretaries of Defense and the Interior should work together to develop a process by which future repairs and necessary modifications to the Memorial can be achieved in as timely and cost-effective a manner as possible.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c111:H.R.1044:"/></bill>
