<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="111" type="h" number="1135" abbrev="H.R. 1135"><status date="2009-02-23">introduced</status><introduced date="2009-02-23"/><title>Bus Uniform Standards and Enhanced Safety Act of 2009</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="111" type="h" number="1396"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>Transportation and public works</subject><subject>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</subject><subject>Business investment and capital</subject><subject>Department of Transportation</subject><subject>Government information and archives</subject><subject>Government investigations</subject><subject>Government lending and loan guarantees</subject><subject>Health information and medical records</subject><subject>Health personnel</subject><subject>Income tax credits</subject><subject>Licensing and registrations</subject><subject>Medical tests and diagnostic methods</subject><subject>Motor carriers</subject><subject>Motor vehicles</subject><subject>Small business</subject><subject>Transportation employees</subject><subject>Transportation programs funding</subject><subject>Transportation safety and security</subject></subjects><summary>2/23/2009--Introduced.
Bus Uniform Standards and Enhanced Safety Act of 2009 or the BUSES Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations to require: (1) monitoring of the safety performance of motorcoach service providers and other commercial motor carriers of passengers; and (2) progressive interventions to correct unsafe practices, and if they are not corrected, an enforcement action. Authorizes the Secretary to organize special enforcement strike forces to target commercial motor vehicle operators when appropriate. Directs the Secretary to: (1) prescribe regulations to establish minimum training requirements for motorcoach drivers; (2) review testing requirements for a commercial driver's license passenger endorsement; (3) develop requirements for the testing of medical examiners who examine commercial motor vehicle operators for physical fitness and seek to be listed in the national registry; (4) review annually the implementation of the commercial driver's license requirements of at least 10 states to assess the validity of physical examination reports and medical certificates submitted by certified medical examiners; and (5) establish the national registry of medical examiners. Sets forth additional Medical Review Board functions. Requires the Secretary to review and report to Congress on federal commercial motor vehicle safety inspection standards. Revises federal motor carrier registration requirements. Directs the Secretary to prescribe federal motor vehicle safety standards for occupant protection systems for new and existing motorcoaches. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a qualified motorcoach safety credit to a taxpayer for the costs of new and existing motorcoaches to comply with the federal motor vehicle safety standards. Requires the Secretary to provide grants (not to exceed $20,000 per vehicle) to motorcoach operators to assist with the cost of retrofitting motorcoaches in order to comply with such federal standards. Amends the Small Business Act to grant the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) the authority to make SBA loans and loan guarantees to motorcoach operators to retrofit their buses and motorcoaches for occupant protection.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c111:H.R.1135:"/></bill>
