<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="111" type="h" number="1210" abbrev="H.R. 1210"><status date="2010-09-30T00:47:00-04:00">vote</status><introduced date="2009-02-26"/><title>Arthritis Prevention, Control, and Cure Act of 2009</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="111" type="s" number="984"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>Health</subject><subject>Child health</subject><subject>Government information and archives</subject><subject>Health care coverage and access</subject><subject>Health information and medical records</subject><subject>Health personnel</subject><subject>Health programs administration and funding</subject><subject>Health promotion and preventive care</subject><subject>Medical education</subject><subject>Medical research</subject><subject>Musculoskeletal and skin diseases</subject><subject>Research administration and funding</subject><subject>Student aid and college costs</subject></subjects><summary>9/30/2010--Passed House amended. Arthritis Prevention, Control, and Cure Act of 2010 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop and implement a National Arthritis Action Plan. Authorizes the Secretary, directly or through competitive grants, to conduct, support, and promote the coordination of research, investigations, demonstrations, training, and studies relating to the control, prevention, and surveillance of arthritis and other rheumatic diseases. Permits the Secretary, upon request of a grantee, to provide training, technical assistance, supplies, equipment, or services or detail any officer or employee of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to aid the grantee in carrying out grant activities. Requires the Secretary to reduce the amount of payments under the grant by an amount equal to the costs of detailing personnel and the fair market value of any supplies, equipment, or services provided by the Secretary. Authorizes the Secretary to provide additional grant support to encourage the expansion of research related to the prevention and management of arthritis at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Authorizes the Secretary to coordinate and carry out national education and outreach activities for arthritis and other rheumatic diseases, which may include public awareness campaigns, public service announcements, and community partnership workshops. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) emphasize prevention, early diagnosis, and appropriate management of arthritis and opportunities for effective patient self-management; and (2) give priority to reaching high-risk or underserved populations. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to a state or Indian tribe to provide support for comprehensive arthritis control and prevention programs and to enable such state or Indian tribe to provide public health surveillance, prevention, and control activities related to arthritis and other rheumatic diseases. Authorizes appropriations for FY2012-FY2016. (Sec. 3) Authorizes the Secretary to expand and intensify programs of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) with respect to research and related activities designed to improve the outcomes and quality of life for children with arthritis and other rheumatic diseases. (Sec. 4) Authorizes the Secretary to award institutional training grants to institutions to support pediatric rheumatology training to ensure an adequate future supply of pediatric rheumatologists.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c111:H.R.1210:"/></bill>
