<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="110" type="h" number="1051" abbrev="H.R. 1051"><status date="2007-06-06T10:57:00-04:00">vote</status><introduced date="2007-02-14"/><title>National STEM Scholarship Database Act</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="110" type="s" number="2392"/><relatedbill session="110" type="s" number="2428"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>Education</subject><subject>Data banks</subject><subject>Economics and public finance</subject><subject>Electronic government information</subject><subject>Electronic mail systems</subject><subject>Engineering</subject><subject>Federal aid to education</subject><subject>Government contractors</subject><subject>Government operations and politics</subject><subject>Government publicity</subject><subject>Higher education</subject><subject>Mathematics</subject><subject>Minorities</subject><subject>Minority education</subject><subject>Scholarships</subject><subject>Science, technology, communications</subject><subject>Scientific education</subject><subject>Student aid</subject><subject>Technical education</subject><subject>Web sites</subject><subject>Women</subject><subject>Women's education</subject></subjects><summary>6/6/2007--Passed House amended. National STEM Scholarship Database Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to establish and maintain, on the public website of the Department of Education, a database of information on public and private programs of financial assistance for the study of postsecondary and graduate science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.
Requires that such database: (1) provide separate information for each field of study; (2) be searchable by category and combinations of categories; (3) indicate programs targeted toward specific demographic groups; (4) provide searchers with program sponsor contact information and hyperlinks; and (5) include a recommendation that students and families carefully review application requirements and a disclaimer that scholarships presented in the database are not provided or endorsed by the Department or the federal government.
Requires the Secretary and the entity contracted to furnish and regularly update information to consult with public and private sources of scholarships and make easily available a process for the sources to provide regular and updated information.
Authorizes appropriations.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c110:H.R.1051:"/></bill>
