<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="110" type="h" number="1063" abbrev="H.R. 1063"><status date="2007-02-15">introduced</status><introduced date="2007-02-15"/><title>Child Interstate Abortion Notification Act</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="110" type="s" number="2543"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>Criminal justice</subject><subject>Abortion</subject><subject>Actions and defenses</subject><subject>Children</subject><subject>Families</subject><subject>Fines (Penalties)</subject><subject>Incest</subject><subject>Law</subject><subject>Minors</subject><subject>Parent and child</subject><subject>Physicians</subject><subject>State and local government</subject><subject>State laws</subject><subject>Transportation</subject></subjects><summary>2/15/2007--Introduced.
Child Interstate Abortion Notification Act - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit transporting a minor child across a state line to obtain an abortion (deems such transporting to be a de facto abridgment of the right of a parent under any law in the minor&#x2019;s state of residence that requires parental involvement in the minor&#x2019;s abortion decision). Makes an exception for an abortion necessary to safe the life of the minor. Makes it an affirmative defense to a prosecution or civil action under this Act that a defendant: (1) reasonably believed that before the minor obtained the abortion, the required parental consent or notification or judicial authorization took place; or (2) was presented with documentation showing that a court waived parental notification requirements or authorized the minor's abortion.
Defines "abortion" as the termination of a pregnancy with an intention other than to increase the probability of a live birth, preserve the life or health of the child after live birth, remove a dead unborn child who died as the result of a spontaneous abortion, accidental trauma, or a criminal assault on the pregnant female or her unborn child. Imposes a fine and/or prison term of up to one year on a physician who performs or induces an abortion on an out-of-state minor in violation of parental notification requirements. Requires such physician to give 24-hour actual or constructive notice to a parent of the minor seeking an abortion, subject to certain exceptions.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c110:H.R.1063:"/></bill>
