<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="110" type="h" number="1100" abbrev="H.R. 1100"><status date="2007-05-23T16:46:00-04:00">vote</status><introduced date="2007-02-15"/><title>Carl Sandburg Home National Historic Site Boundary Revision Act of 2007</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="110" type="hr" number="429"/><relatedbill session="110" type="s" number="488"/><relatedbill session="110" type="s" number="488"/><relatedbill session="110" type="s" number="2739"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>Public lands and natural resources</subject><subject>Arts, culture, religion</subject><subject>Authors and authorship</subject><subject>Commemorations</subject><subject>Historic sites</subject><subject>History</subject><subject>Land transfers</subject><subject>North Carolina</subject><subject>Parking facilities</subject><subject>Poetry</subject><subject>Tourism</subject><subject>Transportation and public works</subject></subjects><summary>9/17/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on May 17, 2007. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Carl Sandburg Home National Historic Site Boundary Revision Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire from willing sellers by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange not more than 110 acres of certain land, water, or interests in land and water to be added to the Carl Sandburg Home National Historic Site. Permits the Secretary, in order to preserve the historic character and landscape of the Site, to also acquire up to five acres of land for the development of a visitor center and visitor parking area adjacent to or in the vicinity of the Site. Instructs the Secretary, upon the acquisition of any land or interest in land under this Act, to revise the boundary of the Site to reflect the acquisition. Requires any land added to the Site by this Act to be administered as part of the Site in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c110:H.R.1100:"/></bill>
