<?xml version="1.0"?>
<bill session="110" type="h" number="1198" abbrev="H.R. 1198"><status date="2008-04-08T15:14:00-04:00">vote</status><introduced date="2007-02-27"/><title>Early Hearing Detection and Intervention Act of 2007</title><relatedbills><relatedbill session="110" type="s" number="1069"/></relatedbills><subjects><subject>Health</subject><subject>Access to health care</subject><subject>Authorization</subject><subject>Child health</subject><subject>Cost effectiveness</subject><subject>Data banks</subject><subject>Deaf</subject><subject>Department of Health and Human Services</subject><subject>Disabled</subject><subject>Economics and public finance</subject><subject>Education</subject><subject>Families</subject><subject>Family services</subject><subject>Federal aid to research</subject><subject>Government operations and politics</subject><subject>Grants-in-aid</subject><subject>Hearing</subject><subject>Higher education</subject><subject>Infants</subject><subject>Language and languages</subject><subject>Medical education</subject><subject>Medical personnel</subject><subject>Medical records</subject><subject>Medical research</subject><subject>Medical screening</subject><subject>Medical tests</subject><subject>Performance measurement</subject><subject>Policy sciences</subject><subject>Quality of care</subject><subject>Recruiting of employees</subject><subject>Research and development</subject><subject>Research grants</subject><subject>Scholarships</subject><subject>Science, technology, communications</subject></subjects><summary>4/8/2008--Passed House amended. Early Hearing Detection and Intervention Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to expand the newborns and infants hearing loss program to include diagnostic services among the services provided. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), to assist in the recruitment, retention, education, and training of qualified personnel and health care providers. Includes within the purposes of such program: (1) prompt evaluation and diagnosis of children referred from screening programs; (2) appropriate education, audiological, and medical interventions for children identified with hearing loss; (3) developing efficient models to ensure that newborns and infants who are identified with a hearing loss through screening receive follow-up by a qualified health care provider; and (4) ensuring an adequate supply of qualified personnel to meet the screening, evaluation, and early intervention needs of children. Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), acting through the Director of the National Institute on Deafness and Other Communication Disorders, to establish a postdoctoral fellowship program to foster research and development in the area of early hearing detection and intervention. Amends the definition of "early intervention" to require that families be given the opportunity to obtain the full range of appropriate early intervention services, educational and program placements, and other options for their child from highly qualified providers. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2014 for hearing screening programs and research.</summary><link href="http://thomas.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/z?c110:H.R.1198:"/></bill>
